<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 10:03:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Migrants at Sea: Unintended Consequences of Search and Rescue Operations by Naveen K]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In the West, has there been a system more thoroughly fraud-ridden, universally known to be fraudulent, with enormous humanitarian costs, fiscal costs, political stability costs, social trust costs, and social welfare costs than asylum system?</p>
<p>Quite literally, it is universally fraudulent and universally used as a trojan horse for illegal immigration yet not a single Western government has banned this or even reformed this through legislation. Remain in Mexico is a stopgap executive order measure. Has any Western government prosecuted NGOs that enable this for undermining the sovereignty of their own nation? If I smuggle migrants, I can face prison (but rarely do) but if I provide material support and coach migrants while drawing a salary as an NGO activist, it is completely legal and my non-profit or NGO is often funded with taxpayer dollars.</p>
<p>It is getting so shameless to the point where I recently heard from a Indian guy I met in Loudon County, VA that his brother-in-law who is a "student" in Canada is applying for asylum in Canada to avoid deportation. He stated it as a matter-of-fact and didn't feel any shame in telling me this as it is quite common now. In 2022 <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/canada-calling-international-students-asylum-9217912/" rel="nofollow ugc">3,500 Indian students applied for asylum</a>. </p>
<p>Asylum is golden key to bypass every single immigration control. Just scrap all asylum (and refugee) laws altogether. I have no faith any reforms which have been promised by parties for many years and haven't happened yet.</p>
<p>Scap asylum laws. Do not rescue the boats. Do not let migrants across the southern border. Mass deportation and remigration. Any other is just inviting a moral hazard and unacceptable.</p>
<p>P.S. Even legal immigration from MENA is a social and moral disaster. See Sweden bombings. Crime in every nation that has taken in MENA legal migration like Germany is dominated by MENA migrants. Let's not lose sight of this either.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752649">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752649</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations</a></p><p>Votes: 328⬆ 22⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752649</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752649</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Naveen K]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 05:57:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Migrants at Sea: Unintended Consequences of Search and Rescue Operations by RAD]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Speaking of shameless, here is Naveen K:</p>
<blockquote><p>He stated it as a matter-of-fact and didn't feel any shame in telling me this as it is quite common now. In 2022 3,500 Indian students applied for asylum [after being misled/scammed by Conestoga College and/or exploitive student "agents" in India].</p>
<p>Asylum is golden key to bypass every single immigration control. <b>Just</b> scrap all asylum (and refugee) laws altogether.</p></blockquote>
<p>Shameless instigators of outrage tend to begin their policy prescriptions with "just..." but ignore the critical factors, like the mismatch highlighted in the linked article:</p>
<blockquote><p>However, that dream has turned into a mirage. For even though Canada is accepting more immigrants than ever before, the system hasn’t been able to keep pace with the numbers of students coming in. As things stand, roughly three out of every 10 international students will likely get permanent residency.</p></blockquote>
<p>Asymmetrical information and negative sum smugglers, scammers, and border coyotes are the key problems. Unfortunately, all value chains are targets of negative sum gamification that ultimately diminishes the true value underpinning these institutions. Truly deserving asylum seekers, skilled foreign workers, and international students with high potential are the ultimate losers. </p>
<p>These are wicked problems requiring thoughtfully designed, implemented, and executed policy solutions, not flippant hand-waving. YMMV.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752669">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752669</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations</a></p><p>Votes: 261⬆ 16⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752669</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752669</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[RAD]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 08:49:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Migrants at Sea: Unintended Consequences of Search and Rescue Operations by M]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>At the end of the day prior, those that don't offer a real ultimate solution will be sidelined.</p>
<p>If you fantasize and hold forth about 1984 futures of machine gunning in the Mediterranean sea, you will be ignored in favour of eagle eyed people noticing the actual machine guns and grenades in Stockholm.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752677">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752677</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations</a></p><p>Votes: 245⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752677</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752677</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[M]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 09:51:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Migrants at Sea: Unintended Consequences of Search and Rescue Operations by Did you eagle eye miss this?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Sept 23, 2023 - "A Libyan coast guard boat rammed into a dingy carrying some 50 migrants just off Libya’s coast on Friday, partially sinking the vessel. Many of those onboard were thrown into the Mediterranean Sea and had to swim to another Libyan ship nearby for safety, a rescue group said.</p>
<p>It appeared to be the latest reckless sea interception of migrants by the Libyan coast guard, which is trained and financed by the European Union to stem the influx of migrants to Europe."</p>
<p>Or maybe this from 2021? - "Footage has emerged that appears to show the Libyan coastguard firing on a boat in distress carrying migrant families in the Mediterranean Sea.</p>
<p>Rescue workers from the German organisation Sea-Watch recorded the coastguard patrol vessel apparently trying to ram the small wooden boat and firing shots in an attempt to force the people onboard back to Libya."</p>
<p>As Tyler likes to say, it's already happening.</p>
<p>And don't forget anti-tank rockets. Biker gangs in Scandinavia are well armed. "The Nordic Biker War was a gang war that began in January 1994 and continued until September 1997 in parts of Scandinavia and Finland, involving the Hells Angels and Bandidos outlaw motorcycle clubs. The conflict is also known as the Great Nordic Biker War or Second Biker War (Danish: anden rockerkrig) to distinguish it from the earlier Copenhagen Biker War, which took place between 1983 and 1985.</p>
<p>The conflict arose from disputes over territory and organized crime rackets, as well as personal feuds within the biker subculture. Specifically, the members of both groups sought a monopoly on the right to engage in crime in certain geographical areas. The war resulted in the killings of nine gang members, with shootings and bombings totalling another 74 attempted murders. The bikers utilized car bombs, machine guns, hand grenades, anti-tank missiles and small arms during their gang war, and assassination attempts were even made inside prisons. The majority of the hostilities took place in or around Copenhagen in Denmark, Helsinki in Finland, Oslo in Norway, and Helsingborg in Sweden."</p>
<p>The Somalis are punks in comparison.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752685">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752685</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations</a></p><p>Votes: 228⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752685</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/migrants-at-sea-unintended-consequences-of-search-and-rescue-operations.html?commentID=160752685</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Did you eagle eye miss this?]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 10:27:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on What is the problem in Australia? (from my email) by RAD]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Live in the future, then build what's missing.<br />
— <a href="https://paulgraham.com/startupideas.html" rel="nofollow ugc">Paul Graham</a> (riffing off of Robert Pirsig and Paul Buchheit)</p></blockquote>
<p>Carpe diem, baby. The Anglosphere is embarking on a Great Pivot. In the aftermath of the Great Recession we were contemplating <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2010/07/the-end-of-men/308135/" rel="nofollow ugc">The End of Men</a>. Now it looks like training enough skilled tradesmen for the next three decades is our greatest challenge. Boo, effin, hoo. Hard things are hard. Twas ever thus. </p>
<p>Don't look a gift horse in the mouth. Time to build. Pitter patter, let's get at'er. YMMV.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?commentID=160752531">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?commentID=160752531</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email</a></p><p>Votes: 335⬆ 7⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?commentID=160752531</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?commentID=160752531</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[RAD]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 21:48:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on What is the problem in Australia? (from my email) by Guyren Howe]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>US Deaths from Covid to date: 1,161,164 (~3,500 deaths per million)<br />
Australia Deaths from Covid to date: 20,272 (~764 deaths per million)</p>
<p>Australians are generally supportive of the country’s response to Covid, and it’s hard to argue it wasn’t effective.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?commentID=160752451">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?commentID=160752451</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email</a></p><p>Votes: 341⬆ 21⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?commentID=160752451</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?commentID=160752451</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Guyren Howe]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 19:41:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on What is the problem in Australia? (from my email) by blue jay]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>"I think about how much corporate leaders make. "</p>
<p>If you're comparing to US corps, no, Australia doesn't have that because it has one company in the world's top 100 companies whilte the US has over 60 in the top 100.  Australia does not have a single major company in any aspect of technology and it's only top 100 co is BHP, a mining company.  </p>
<p>So the obvious reason Australian CEO's would be at the bottom of the pay barrel is because, appart from BHP, they're at the bottom of the value barrel and mostly unable to compete outside Australia</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?commentID=160752523">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?commentID=160752523</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email</a></p><p>Votes: 315⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?commentID=160752523</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/what-is-the-problem-in-australia-from-my-email.html?commentID=160752523</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[blue jay]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 21:32:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by peri]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I don't know. Back when the numbers of homeless were so much smaller, among the men - the women were always obviously crazy - you kind of got an "urban outdoorsman" vibe. They actually carried their stuff on their back, instead of in five shopping carts and a kiddie bike roped together. They seemed to know and practice the art, many of them, of blending in.<br />
I remember walking through a park and noticing a couple homeless guys actually cooking a squirrel on the charcoal grill.<br />
It doesn't seem much like that now.<br />
Even when they are sitting around, in their chairs, with a rug and a TV, on the actual overpass of the freeway, smiling and laughing - they remind me most of the crazy guy who used to be in the laundromate all the time when I was doing laundry, *pretending* to hold a conversation on the payphone. For hours.<br />
I do think they have some skills, though. They are hardy, obviously, and to an extent brave since one of them kills another one approximately every four or five days, you know, just like their community was Stars Hollow. </p>
<p>But overall, the salient fact is they are drawn to precincts where rich people are. Full stop. They are never anywhere else but there. </p>
<p>That's not something you could have ever said about a "frontiersman".</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?commentID=160752478">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?commentID=160752478</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-451">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-451</a></p><p>Votes: 301⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?commentID=160752478</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?commentID=160752478</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[peri]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 20:16:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by mkt42]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>"5. A movie about Carlsen-Niemann?"</p>
<p>"A24 dove in with what sources say was an offer that guaranteed seven figures, and came in with a 30 minutes timer"</p>
<p>Does that mean A24 enclosed a chess clock with their offer?  Or does it mean A24 said that they had only 30 minutes to respond, or the offer would be withdrawn?</p>
<p>"It was an offer that was swiftly accepted."</p>
<p>So maybe the latter?  But complex business decisions take more than 30 minutes to process.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?commentID=160752419">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?commentID=160752419</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-451">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-451</a></p><p>Votes: 299⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?commentID=160752419</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?commentID=160752419</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[mkt42]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 18:44:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by Lord Action]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>"It was Reagan that famously emptied the psychiatric hospitals"</p>
<p>I'm aware.  The media was full of critiques of the care of the mentally ill in those days.  The film One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest is a famous example.</p>
<p>FWIW, I don't think this was some fringe thing back when it was done.   People really thought it would be better.</p>
<p>The climate is changing today.  But even now, you see people who still defend drug legalization and decriminalization, for example.  We aren't out of the woods yet.  Probably drug abuse is the worse problem than mental illness today, but both are important.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?commentID=160752519">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?commentID=160752519</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-451">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-451</a></p><p>Votes: 299⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?commentID=160752519</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/thursday-assorted-links-451.html?commentID=160752519</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Lord Action]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 21:25:51 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>