<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 10:09:32 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Quantifying the Super-Villains by rayward]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The medical devices in this study reefer to "durable medical equipment" (DME). DME includes medical devices for home use, such as insulin pumps, CPAP machines, oxygen concentrators, hospital beds, crutches, walkers, and wheelchairs. Depending on the type, DME is reimbursed by Medicare and Medicaid. DME providers are regulated at the federal level and by most states (including Florida). Just the same, the DME industry is a very big problem, not only the enormous growth and not simply price gouging but fraud such as payments ("kickbacks") to medical providers to induce the providers to recommend or use particular devices. How to address the problem is the subject of this study: the government chose the blunt instrument of across the board cuts in reimbursement. According to the authors, the savings from the cuts are more than offset by a reduction in innovations in the DME industry. </p>
<p>Reimbursement for DME is part of the effort by government to get patients out of the hospital, the hospital being the black hole for medical spending. The entire home health care sector is part of this effort. What happened is that the black hole was replaced with an industry that is fraught with fraud, from overcharging to "kickbacks".  This subject is way too complex to address in a comment, but must be viewed in the broader context. Maybe the blunt instrument isn't the most efficient method, but it most definitely has discouraged growth of the DME industry.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/quantifying-the-super-villains.html?commentID=160826154">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/quantifying-the-super-villains.html?commentID=160826154</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/quantifying-the-super-villains.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=quantifying-the-super-villains">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/quantifying-the-super-villains.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=quantifying-the-super-villains</a></p><p>Votes: 48⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/quantifying-the-super-villains.html?commentID=160826154</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/quantifying-the-super-villains.html?commentID=160826154</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[rayward]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 09:14:13 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>