<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 10:07:54 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Organize your life? by GoodSpirit]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I remember seeing that guy's Tweet about his life-organizing Notion doc a few weeks ago, and noted then how people were really lashing out, calling it dystopian, the worst thing they had ever seen, etc. Came across as really mean-spirited. Kudos to him for being brave enough to speak to the NYT about it, as they could have totally hit-pieced him (wouldn't be the first time). I'm always surprise by the things that make people fly off the handle.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160756774">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160756774</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=organize-your-life">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=organize-your-life</a></p><p>Votes: 342⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160756774</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160756774</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[GoodSpirit]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 08:49:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Organize your life? by 85 IQ Internet User]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Feels very much like slavery. A eunuch slave bureaucrat would need to do this. A tiger would never need a schedule. I’d rather keep being retarded thank you very much</p>
<p>On the other hand I really respect this level of autism. To each his own :)</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160756838">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160756838</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=organize-your-life">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=organize-your-life</a></p><p>Votes: 300⬆ 8⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160756838</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160756838</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[85 IQ Internet User]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 12:43:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Organize your life? by Hazel Meade]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Dinwar:</p><blockquote><p>An alternative viewpoint: </p>
<p>https://www.artofmanliness.com/character/behavior/sunday-firesides-stop-the-vivisection-of-beauty/</p>
<p>Part of the hate is the idea that you can engineer life. It's tempting--I'm a project manager, and believe me, it's tempting to use those skills in my personal life. But the VAST majority of people do not like being engineered. A certain amount of intentionality is necessary in a romantic relationship, sure, but a certain amount needs to be organic. How much of each is something that each couple needs to decide for themselves. </p>
<p>Reminds me of the guy who wrote "Getting Things Done". He said in the book that he and his wife put things in each other's "In" box, as a sign of respect for the other person's time. Works for them I guess--if you marry someone who's job is to design productivity systems you sort of have to expect this sort of behavior--but it's not going to be something that most people will tolerate.</p>
<p>As a project manager I have certain resources and certain concrete goals, and my job is to accomplish those goals within those resources. And romantic relationships simply are not like that. Getting to know another person is a lifelong endeavor. Building a life with someone isn't something you can expect a 6% margin on. These tools can be applied to some limited aspects of romantic relationships--like, I'm putting together a cost estimate for some remodeling, and the tools I use at work are as good a framework as anything else--but how do you forecast the love you feel for a child? Once you break down love into critical path items it stops being love. </p>
<p>If it works for him and his spouse that's fantastic for them. Seriously, it's great! But the idea that it's going to be widely applicable defies pretty much everything we know about human nature. Every relationship is unique, and every relationship has to find its own equilibrium.</p>
</blockquote><p>The thing is if you are really, really, really effing busy, you actually DO need to schedule time for important things like "find someone to marry and have kids with". It's a really problem for very busy people. And it actually is useful at that point to manage it using the same tools you would use for project management.<br />
Project: find romantic partner before too old to have kids. Schedule: coffee dates with these 10 people I picked off of OK Cupid. Etc. </p>
<p>Same thing if you have kids already and need to schedule time for "date nights" to keep from getting a divorce. You have to arrange baby sitters, get tickets or reservations for wherever. Maybe rent a hotel room for a night. Whatever. Two people with full time jobs and three kids that have soccer, dance, swim, music whatever lessons requires time management. The fact that their lives are that busy and they need this is not a ding against their personalities.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160756883">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160756883</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=organize-your-life">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=organize-your-life</a></p><p>Votes: 275⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160756883</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160756883</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Hazel Meade]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:51:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Organize your life? by Hazel Meade]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to mkt42:</p><blockquote><p>Hmm, when Tyler and MR commenters praise Musk for playing 3-D chess, I hadn't thought about that angle.  </p>
<p>First level:  Musk is a genius, he'll improve Twitter.</p>
<p>Second level (where I'm at):  Musk is impulsive and id-driven, and made a seat-of-the-pants decision, and a very bad one, and has lost tens of billions of dollars in lost Twitter value.</p>
<p>Third level (what you're hypothesizing):  this was Musk's game all along, to eliminate Twitter as a relevant player in society.  </p>
<p>Tyler is such a fan-boy of Musk that he accused Musk's critics of having Elon Derangement Syndrome.  I wonder if Tyler is clinging to this level 3 hypothesis. </p>
<p>However, Tyler was and is a fan of Twitter, pre- and post-Musk, so I don't see Tyler being in favor of Musk's Twitter-destroying strategy, if indeed that's what Musk is trying to do.</p>
</blockquote><p>Yeah, I don't think Tyler thinks Musk is intentionally destroying Twitter as a favor to society. But to me, it seem obvious. He renamed it "X" for example. Come on. That's telegraphing "I'm planning to ruin this thing" right off the bat.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160757169">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160757169</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=organize-your-life">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=organize-your-life</a></p><p>Votes: 100⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160757169</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/organize-your-life.html?commentID=160757169</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Hazel Meade]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 01:18:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Jerry Seinfeld Duke commencement speech by Marky Mark]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>These are deeply unfunny times. </p>
<p>In Jesse David Fox's 2024 Comedy Book, Jerry Seinfeld and his humor is given much attention. </p>
<p>Fox writes, "Comedy Central’s head of research, Chanon Cook, speaking about a 2012 survey she conducted, which showed that millennials viewed humor as the number-one factor in their self-definition. “Comedy is to this generation what music was to previous generations,” she told me. “They use it to define themselves. They use it to connect with people.” Comedy Central called them Comedy Natives.</p>
<p>"By 2014, comedy was seen as so important politically that when the Obama administration was desperate to boost Affordable Care Act enrollment, their bright idea was to have the president appear on Zach Galifianakis’s talk show parody, Between Two Ferns, which featured jokes like “What is it like to be the last Black president?” And it worked, with the Healthcare.gov site experiencing a 40 percent boost in traffic, almost entirely made up of people who had never visited the site before. The American socialist magazine Jacobin would later call it “The Day Zach Galifianakis Saved Obamacare.”</p>
<p>It is truly astonishing that comedy is so important to this generation.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?commentID=160756758">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?commentID=160756758</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech</a></p><p>Votes: 260⬆ 10⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?commentID=160756758</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?commentID=160756758</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Marky Mark]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 07:10:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Jerry Seinfeld Duke commencement speech by M]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Some recent headlines over the last week:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/10/world/middleeast/un-resolution-palestinian.html" rel="nofollow ugc">U.N. General Assembly Adopts Resolution in Support of Palestinian Statehood</a> </p>
<p><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-68984999" rel="nofollow ugc">US says Israel may have breached international law with American weapons in Gaza</a> </p>
<p><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/netanyahu-war-crimes-investigation-puts-biden-tough-spot-1897718" rel="nofollow ugc">Netanyahu War Crimes Investigation Puts Biden in Tough Spot</a></p>
<p>...</p>
<p>"It's happening" as some might say. (Chickens and roosting).</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?commentID=160756757">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?commentID=160756757</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech</a></p><p>Votes: 252⬆ 43⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?commentID=160756757</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?commentID=160756757</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[M]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 07:05:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Jerry Seinfeld Duke commencement speech by Slocum]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Todd K:</p><blockquote><p>I'm not surprised that Cowen links to a billionaire telling graduates to quit their jobs if they don't like them. "If you stay at a job that you don't like, that's your fault!"</p>
</blockquote><p>There is, of course, an intense survivorship bias in graduation speakers.  Who knows how many other aspiring comedians started out at the same time as Seinfeld, desperate to succeed in a 'cool job' and living on peanut butter?   The vast majority never made it and may have wasted irrecoverable years pursing an unrealizable dream.  But graduates only hear from one of the tiny few with the right combination of talent and luck to end up vastly rich and successful.  Well, hopefully, the graduates have the good sense to ignore that part of his advice.  And it's still, one of the better graduation speeches I've ever heard.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?commentID=160756789">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?commentID=160756789</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech</a></p><p>Votes: 202⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?commentID=160756789</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/jerry-seinfeld-duke-commencement-speech.html?commentID=160756789</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Slocum]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 10:37:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Just to confirm… by Shark Lasers]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to wow:</p><blockquote><p>Shark Lasers: "hey I hate the climate change theory and those dirty immigrants, how can I mix these two and present it as the way that fits my narrative while owning libs?"</p>
</blockquote><p>Well they aren't going to ban private jet travel, that's for sure.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?commentID=160756586">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?commentID=160756586</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=just-to-confirm">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=just-to-confirm</a></p><p>Votes: 387⬆ 8⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?commentID=160756586</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?commentID=160756586</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Shark Lasers]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 19:25:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Just to confirm… by BlueSilverWave]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I can't express how much #3 here is bullshit. Average new car transaction price is around 49k. EVs that start MSRP less than that (prior to ev credit):<br />
Nissan Leaf (28k)<br />
Hyundai Kona (33)<br />
Volvo EX30 (35k)<br />
Hyundai Ioniq 6 (38)<br />
Tesla Model 3 (39k)<br />
Kia Niro (39k)<br />
VW ID.4 (40k)<br />
Nissan Ariya (40k)<br />
Ford Mach-E (40k)<br />
Chevy Equinox (41k)<br />
Hyundai Ioniq 5 (42k)<br />
Toyota bZ4X (43k) (yes they actually named it that)<br />
Kia EV6 (43k)<br />
Subaru Solterra (45k)<br />
Tesla Model Y (45k)<br />
Honda Prologue (47k)<br />
Chevy Blazer (49k)</p>
<p>Nationwide there are over 31k new EVs on AutoTrader on dealer lots for under $50k. This doesn't cover the large number of lightly used EVs out there available too.</p>
<p>Adoption hasn't slowed because of lack of low-cost options. Adoption has slowed because the charging infrastructure sucks and most people don't want to pay another &gt;$5k in cash right now to retrofit a decent charger to their house.</p>
<p>We've just saturated the Early Adopters, and haven't started into the Early Majority yet. The vehicles that the Innovators and Early Adopters are willing to live with (Spark EV, first gen Leaf) and the compromises (Supercharger, Electrify America, and other ABSOLUTE JOKES) aren't things Early / Late Majority are willing to put up with (hence the used prices)</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?commentID=160756578">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?commentID=160756578</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=just-to-confirm">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=just-to-confirm</a></p><p>Votes: 385⬆ 11⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?commentID=160756578</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?commentID=160756578</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[BlueSilverWave]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 19:15:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Just to confirm… by Shark Lasers]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Fun fact: you can do this with all sorts of policies pushed by our overlords.</p>
<p>For example, if climate change is an unprecedented risk, it's probably not wise to import millions of people from low-carbon third-world societies into the high-carbon West.</p>
<p>But it turns out that people like Tyler are only interested in pointing out the absurdities in their logic when it comes to safe topics like trade protectionism.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?commentID=160756528">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?commentID=160756528</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=just-to-confirm">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=just-to-confirm</a></p><p>Votes: 442⬆ 77⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?commentID=160756528</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/just-to-confirm.html?commentID=160756528</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Shark Lasers]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 18:32:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Sunday assorted links by Ai]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>1. I’m pretty sure this is just openness to experience being correlated with both 1) creativity/open-mindedness and 2) liberal social and political attitudes. But this schema doesn’t necessarily track perfectly with today’s political stereotypes. For example, works that stick to the liberal party line in the most straightforward way (like Don’t Look Up, Black Panther, the Ghost Busters remakes, etc.) are just as artistically bankrupt as the most sentimental conservative movies. An open mind that’s attracted to complexity and ambiguity in entertainment is probably going to be turned off by the simplistic and polarizing extremes of both the left and the right.</p>
<p>5. Also, when’s the last time that an instrumental song reached the top 10? Or a ballad? Or a song with a guitar solo? Or a saxophone solo? Or any instrumental solo part? Or harmonized vocals? Popular tastes in music change so much over the years, it’s amazing to me when I think back to songs that were huge hits when I was a kid, like “You Light Up My Life” or “Sailing,” which be unimaginable in the context of today’s pop music.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?commentID=160756585">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?commentID=160756585</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=sunday-assorted-links-468">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=sunday-assorted-links-468</a></p><p>Votes: 277⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?commentID=160756585</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?commentID=160756585</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ai]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 19:24:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Sunday assorted links by Dave T]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Aristophanes:</p><blockquote><p>The stat is "Billboard Top 100 Number 1 hits". So it only counts songs that hit #1. (If the pattern for all top 100 hits was markedly different though, that would be interesting).</p>
</blockquote><p>A broder metric would be better, I suspect it would also show a declining trend, though of course not going to zero.</p>
<p>My take on underlying reasons:</p>
<p>- Increase in % of hits that are rap songs. Rap doesn't really have covers. (Rap songs do, however, often sample well-known songs. That's essentially rap's version of "covers".)</p>
<p>- Rise of streaming services. The older original songs are now readily available. Indeed, can sometimes cause a bit of confusion when searching for a cover song on Spotify or Apple Music. Particularly if the style of the cover isn't that differentiated from the original.</p>
<p>- Think that prevalence of hit cover songs was heavily influenced by common marketing and promotion strategies from major labels, back when those labels dominated the music scene in a way that they no longer do. It could be a "safe" marketing strategy for a cover to be the 2nd or 3rd single from an album. Ties back to the prior point, as a younger generation sometimes might not even be aware that the song is a cover.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?commentID=160756519">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?commentID=160756519</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=sunday-assorted-links-468">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=sunday-assorted-links-468</a></p><p>Votes: 274⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?commentID=160756519</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?commentID=160756519</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dave T]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 18:23:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Sunday assorted links by PaulD]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to mento:</p><blockquote><p>It roughly mirrors their world view  as expected.</p>
<p>Liberals tend to support art that challenges social norms, promotes progressive values, and these days addresses issues like diversity, inclusion, and social justice.<br />
They view art as a catalyst for social change, education, and empowerment, believing it can raise awareness and inspire action on important issues. They like abstract art as it challenges traditional boundaries.</p>
<p>Conservatives tend to perceive  art as a reflection of cultural heritage and values, with an important  role in preserving tradition and fostering national pride.</p>
<p>They will  prefer art that emphasizes traditional values, patriotism (Washington crossing the Delaware) and classical aesthetics. They will be more critical of art that they perceive as politically or socially radical.</p>
</blockquote><p>"Liberals tend to support art that challenges social norms,"  Yes, like making a Madonna out of cow shit, or putting a crucifix in urine.  But, would they dare make a representation of Muhammed out of that or anything else for that matter?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?commentID=160756617">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?commentID=160756617</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=sunday-assorted-links-468">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=sunday-assorted-links-468</a></p><p>Votes: 261⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?commentID=160756617</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/sunday-assorted-links-468.html?commentID=160756617</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[PaulD]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 20:51:06 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>