<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 22:09:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by Crusader]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>2. Some conservatives make the biggest blunders when it comes to education. On one hand they deeply understand and say that most of it is credentialism. And then on the other hand they wonder whether Jordan Peterson’s $500 online course or the University of Austin could work as potential replacements (I’m strawmanning a bit to make a point here)</p>
<p>News flash, it’s the Harvard brand and until you can get anywhere near that level of credentialism, you have nothing. How do you make these alternative education things high status? I have no clue, but perhaps you’d need 100 senior business people to come out and say they’re prioritizing people from X school and treating it as on par with Harvard + direct co-op experiences baked in like Northeastern, but it’s with super top tier firms. Eg Ken Griffin guarantees 10 co-op spots just for kids at this new college, Elon guarantees a bunch of jobs, Marc does too across portcos etc</p>
<p>I disagree with Yarvin on a lot but he did nail this problem that a lot of political activity, on the left and right but usually on the right, is like short-term grift gratification rather than foundational long-term change. He has a riff that if you think the schools are actually that bad and this is all you’re doing about it then you’re either lying or you’re lazy.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/thursday-assorted-links-469.html?commentID=160813651">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/thursday-assorted-links-469.html?commentID=160813651</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/thursday-assorted-links-469.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-469">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/thursday-assorted-links-469.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-469</a></p><p>Votes: 45⬆ 4⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/thursday-assorted-links-469.html?commentID=160813651</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/thursday-assorted-links-469.html?commentID=160813651</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Crusader]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 14:14:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Mercor by hash872]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I’m in the industry. There are dozens and dozens and dozens of platforms that are ‘connecting talent to companies’ (translation, they’ve signed up a few hundred mediocre developers in Hyderabad). The AI interview stuff is mildly interesting if it actually works, but no one’s yet mastered how to properly evaluate software engineers in-person. I don’t think AI is yet at the stage of ‘humans have no idea how to do this, figure it out’. Existing AI interview tech just asks set questions, but without a human in the loop for DEI purposes. Basically, Mercor is probably another recruiting company with a website and AI hype buzzwords</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/mercor.html?commentID=160813568">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/mercor.html?commentID=160813568</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/mercor.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=mercor">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/mercor.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=mercor</a></p><p>Votes: 41⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/mercor.html?commentID=160813568</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/mercor.html?commentID=160813568</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[hash872]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 07:45:10 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>