<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 10:08:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Milei and populism by Seriously?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>‘If his reforms do not succeed, likely it will not be his fault,”</p>
<p>The cop-out for every government and their supporters, ever. Mood affiliation for etc etc…</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/milei-and-populism.html?commentID=160838346">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/milei-and-populism.html?commentID=160838346</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/milei-and-populism.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=milei-and-populism">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/milei-and-populism.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=milei-and-populism</a></p><p>Votes: 60⬆ 11⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/milei-and-populism.html?commentID=160838346</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/milei-and-populism.html?commentID=160838346</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Seriously?]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 07:02:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Friday assorted links by MikeP]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>#1. Why school vouchers failed in Kentucky.</em></p>
<p>Let me go to the single most outlying county in the state, find out why their super-tight community might not like to be shaken up by change, and then post it in a 31-tweet thread phrased like a 3-minute ad video?</p>
<blockquote><p>
Those I talked to did not think it was a coincidence that Kentucky’s smallest county was also the one that rejected the referendum the most decisively.
</p></blockquote>
<p>That makes several of us.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/friday-assorted-links-496.html?commentID=160838131">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/friday-assorted-links-496.html?commentID=160838131</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/friday-assorted-links-496.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=friday-assorted-links-496">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/friday-assorted-links-496.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=friday-assorted-links-496</a></p><p>Votes: 48⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/friday-assorted-links-496.html?commentID=160838131</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/friday-assorted-links-496.html?commentID=160838131</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[MikeP]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 16:34:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Sunstein on DOGE by superdestroyer]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>People should remember that regulations come out of mistakes, disasters, screw up, and issues in the past.  To believe that anyone can step in and just eliminate regulations without knowing the history of the regulation is foolishness.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/sunstein-on-doge.html?commentID=160837971">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/sunstein-on-doge.html?commentID=160837971</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/sunstein-on-doge.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=sunstein-on-doge">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/sunstein-on-doge.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=sunstein-on-doge</a></p><p>Votes: 73⬆ 24⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/sunstein-on-doge.html?commentID=160837971</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/sunstein-on-doge.html?commentID=160837971</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[superdestroyer]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 11:55:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Sunstein on DOGE by Sure]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to superdestroyer:</p><blockquote><p>People should remember that regulations come out of mistakes, disasters, screw up, and issues in the past.  To believe that anyone can step in and just eliminate regulations without knowing the history of the regulation is foolishness.</p>
</blockquote><p>1) I know of plenty of regulations in medicine that exist simply because somebody thought it was a good idea at some point in time. Medical boards, for instance, are required for a lot of stuff for remuneration. Yet they have never been established to result in improved patient care. And if you want to reach back to the hoary olden days ... I would remind you that in the last several decades most medical societies have changed their regulations to make your boards rental property. Apropos of nothing, they just decided that physicians in practice could not be trusted to keep current, and that periodic board testing (collectively costing society billions of dollars) was the answer. Except, many of the societies grandfathered in the old guys such that you literally have physicians who took their initial board one month who have lifetime certification and physicians who took their initial board the next month and have comply with regulations for periodic recertification. </p>
<p>And this is far from unique. When you know the regulations well enough to see the carve outs and the exceptions you can see very handily that a lot of this is politics of some sort. California, for instance, has mandatory maximum nurse to patient ratios that would make all of Europe and most of the rest of the US non-compliant. The data suggesting that this regulation is needed is sorely lacking and appears to be largely the result of political lobbying by nurses' unions.</p>
<p>2) And that lobbying thing is common. A lot of regulations have particular forms because folks with massive financial or political stakes in the regs pulled strings or made threats to get it there. For a while, the best predictor of the practice limitations for nurse practitioners was if the lobby group for physicians or nurses was stronger in a given state. Reporting requirements for intentional or unintentional fetal demise vary overwhelmingly with partisanship and religiosity rather than anything remotely like historical rates of malpractice, maternal mortality, or CDC recommended best practices. </p>
<p>3) Even when regulation was based off historical incidents, it does not mean that the regulations keep current. Take medical communications. Why are physicians still using fax machines in the Year of Our Lord 2024? Because in the 80s we had issues with folks sending medical communications from and to physicians that were not secure, arriving in a timely fashion, or creating a clear chain of notification. Regulations adopted made fax machines a legible safe harbor for such communications. And you are completely safe if you fax some medical communication to a specified fax line; if you have a specified fax line you are clear if somebody tries to communicate with your office. But faxes are no longer particularly timely, they are wildly cumbersome to integrate into various EMRs, and they are even less reliable than a lot of purely digital options. But the regs, for decades, resulted in privileged status and the fax machine was kept front line because of it.  </p>
<p>And, again, this is normal. Nobody needs to know what technical challenges in the 90s resulted in the dominance of the fax machine over email. We just need to draft communication regulations that create clear and compliable expectations. </p>
<p>4) Historical contingency may no longer be informative of the functions regulations currently serve. For instance, medical school accreditation and the standardized four-year curriculum were the result of a bunch of fly-by-night medical schools where students paid by the hour and largely self-determined when they were done studying (with or without some sort of later internship). Flexner wanted to improve public trust in physicians, reduce the supply of physicians, and ensure that physicians were overwhelmingly white. So the requirements for medical schools reflected those goals. Trust in physicians is now much more firmly established via residency requirements and board certification (or so those regulators attest). The supply of physicians has not been constrained by medical schools in decades, instead residency positions are the rate limiter. And, of course, the requirements for full spectrum access to the core clinical clerkships, medical libraries, and the rest have nothing to do with decreasing the number of Black physicians nor limiting their access to highly specialized medical careers. </p>
<p>Instead, the regs have new purposes. Ostensibly to have a unified medical school knowledge set such that any medical student can step into any residency with sufficient knowledge and experience to continue training. The more cynical of us suspect that the old requirements, explicitly put in to discourage for-profit medical education, Black physician training, and female medical training outside of maternal, pediatric, and occupational health were rejustified by regulators to protect their sinecures. </p>
<p>What you really need is to know the goals of the regulations (and I deal with scads of them where I haven't the foggiest, even when I am asked in court to interpret those goals), the common failure modes, and who has interests in the precise manner of regulation. Historical knowledge can be useful, but it is by no means necessary in all (or perhaps even the majority of) cases.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/sunstein-on-doge.html?commentID=160838051">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/sunstein-on-doge.html?commentID=160838051</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/sunstein-on-doge.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=sunstein-on-doge">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/sunstein-on-doge.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=sunstein-on-doge</a></p><p>Votes: 57⬆ 7⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/sunstein-on-doge.html?commentID=160838051</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/11/sunstein-on-doge.html?commentID=160838051</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sure]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:10:26 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>