<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:07:59 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on My excellent Conversation with Philip Ball by PM]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It seems like this might actually be meant ironically or as a kind of quiet critique:</p>
<p>"and I think three of them, so far, have shown they are able to answer any question I might plausibly throw their way. Philip, I believe, is number four."</p>
<p>Only 3 people so far have been so clueless and apparently unable to qualify their own credibility and the bounds of their value that they willingly jump on any question Tyler asks.</p>
<p>In a sense o think that characterizes the conversation. Ball illustrates the silly and common view that Science is an attribute of a person or a group - like a Religion or Party - instead of a way of describing a set of methods for answering questions or a capability that can be applied and mis-applied (like logic).</p>
<p>Clearly he knows and has expertise in specific areas of science and scientific publishing. But then in question after question his answers fall back on some personal opinion that reflects a social value or political sensibility rather than anything remotely similar to a scientific way of unbundling a question and discriminating between forms and levels of evidence.</p>
<p>It's like he thinks he knows Science and therefore any answer he gives is Scientific.</p>
<p>Why would "we" (as I'd there is such a thing) need artificial wombs? </p>
<p>Uhhh, "I dunno" - he doesn't see any reason why it's needed and therefore it isn't. And it isn't possible now, so "it's probably not possible".</p>
<p>Bizarre. </p>
<p>I found this one of the most unimpressive and weirdly (perhaps enlighteningly?) low quality conversations ive heard in a while.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball.html?commentID=160808224">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball.html?commentID=160808224</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball</a></p><p>Votes: 68⬆ 9⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball.html?commentID=160808224</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball.html?commentID=160808224</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[PM]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 05:49:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>