<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 22:06:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Nuclear is Not Best Everywhere by Dinwar]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I like the insulting language used to describe the first three groups. This is not a rational argument; rather, we're supposed to have a knee-jerk reaction of "We're not like that! We're intelligent and thoughtful!" Good rhetorical trick (I mean that, it reminds me of some Roman orators), but one that tells us more about the attitudes of the writers towards those who disagree with them than it does about the counter-arguments the authors are attempting to evade. </p>
<p>Renewable sources have significant problems. They require toxic materials to manufacture (solar panels and turbine components don't spring out of the ground fully-formed). They have gargantuan footprints, with the consequent ecological footprints. Many are highly variable and have limited capacity to ramp up or down as demand requires. Every one of them that I've worked on has had a natural gas fired backup system. Widespread integration into the power grid is not a simple task, nor is it a simple issue to restart the grid if it should be disrupted (see the YouTube channel "Practical Engineering" for a descent discussion of this). Nuclear power has more or less none of these issues, and most of the costs associated with it (as well as the construction delays) are bureaucratic in nature, meaning that if we wanted these plants to cost less they could. </p>
<p>(What's supposed to happen now is that that I'm supposed to fit myself into the "pragmatist" category--an ignorant rube, but with a good heart. Again, it's a good rhetorical trick. It allows the author to No True Scotsman away anyone who disagrees. But it's merely smoke and mirrors, telling you nothing of the realities of the system under discussion.) </p>
<p>I'm actually in favor of diversifying energy sources. The only reason anyone cares about Russia or Iran or a few of our other enemies right now is that oil is valuable; change that, and the foundation of their power evaporates. But let's not delude ourselves about renewables. ALL options here are trade-offs. EVERY option has costs as well as benefits--not infrequently costs that can't be measured in dollars and cents (ask the people who's homes are flooded to make reservoirs if they're happy that power is slightly cheaper for folks who still have homes). We need to be examining this soberly, and while I can appreciate a good rhetorical stratagem someone who opens by slinging insults at everyone who disagrees simply is not doing so.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere.html?commentID=160773012">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere.html?commentID=160773012</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere</a></p><p>Votes: 65⬆ 9⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere.html?commentID=160773012</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere.html?commentID=160773012</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dinwar]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 12:23:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Nuclear is Not Best Everywhere by The Good Bill]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Lefties have been dead wrong on nuclear for 50 years, so it's nice of Alex to group the people who point that out into three condescending categories.  So as to easily rip them.</p>
<p>What's less impressive is to -- once again -- whine that nuclear is "expensive" without stressing that this is only true due the absolutely crushing over-regulation placed on it by the Left.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere.html?commentID=160773003">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere.html?commentID=160773003</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere</a></p><p>Votes: 112⬆ 30⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere.html?commentID=160773003</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/nuclear-is-not-best-everywhere.html?commentID=160773003</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Good Bill]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 12:13:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on 13.9 percent less democracy? by Mikk]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I have to clarify a bit.<br />
In 1940, Estonia was annexed and occupied by the Soviet Union. Most states, including the United States, did not recognize this annexation. De jure, the Estonian Republic continued to exist even though, de facto, it was occupied by the Soviets. When Estonia regained its independence in 1991, it was not considered a new state but rather a continuation of the pre-1940 state. This had many legal consequences. For instance, the Estonian Republic reclaimed its pre-1940 embassy buildings. The United Kingdom returned the gold that the Estonian Republic had deposited in the Bank of England before 1940. People who owned property before 1940 but lost it during the Soviet occupation got their property back, and so on.</p>
<p>One of these legal consequences was that people (mostly Russian speakers) who had arrived during the Soviet occupation did not automatically receive Estonian citizenship. However, citizenship is not denied to them. To obtain Estonian citizenship, there is a residency requirement of 2 or 5 years, and applicants must pass an Estonian language exam. Most Russian speakers have applied for and obtained Estonian citizenship. Those who have not,  6.9% and 7% of the population, have chosen not to do so. Estonian citizenship is not denied to them; they have the right to obtain it but prefer not to.</p>
<p>For instance, stateless persons, while it may sound problematic, have permanent residency in Estonia, which comes with some benefits: they have visa-free access to the European Union and, until recently, also to Russia (Estonian citizens do not have visa-free access to Russia). They have the right to participate in Estonian local elections. As non-citizens, they are not drafted into the Estonian military (Estonia, like Israel and Finland, has mandatory military service). The only right they do not have as non-citizens is the ability to participate in national elections. And guess what? Many people do not care about voting in elections.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/13-9-percent-less-democracy.html?commentID=160772927">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/13-9-percent-less-democracy.html?commentID=160772927</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/13-9-percent-less-democracy.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=13-9-percent-less-democracy">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/13-9-percent-less-democracy.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=13-9-percent-less-democracy</a></p><p>Votes: 79⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/13-9-percent-less-democracy.html?commentID=160772927</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/13-9-percent-less-democracy.html?commentID=160772927</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mikk]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 07:17:04 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>