<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 10:08:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Darien gap fact of the day by PubbyðŸº]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>-</p>
<p>Tyler Cowen leaned back in his chair, eyes glued to the glowing screen before him. His fingers danced across the keyboard, typing out another post for Marginal Revolution, his influential economics blog. As the words flowed effortlessly from his mind to the digital page, a strange feeling began to gnaw at him.</p>
<p>Below the post, a comment section bubbled with life, teeming with opinions both insightful and vitriolic. Tyler's heart raced as he scanned the thread, his mind abuzz with the raw emotion and intellectual debates unfolding before him.</p>
<p>But as the hours passed, the tone grew darker. The smell of anger and farts hung heavy in the virtual air. Tyler's once-exciting routine had become a source of anxiety and stress. He found himself staying up late into the night, unable to tear his gaze away from the comment section.</p>
<p>As the days wore on, Tyler's obsession deepened. He began to consider installing a toilet at his desk, a bold move to ensure he never missed a single comment. But as he pondered this plan, a sudden realization hit him.</p>
<p>This wasn't healthy. He needed to take a step back and focus on his work, his family, and his own well-being. With a deep breath, Tyler closed his laptop and logged off, determined to break free from the comment section's grasp.</p>
<p>But as he turned off the lights and settled into bed, he couldn't shake the feeling that he was missing out on something, some crucial piece of the intellectual puzzle that lay just beyond the screen. And so, the cycle began anew.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/darien-gap-fact-of-the-day.html?commentID=160799624">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/darien-gap-fact-of-the-day.html?commentID=160799624</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/darien-gap-fact-of-the-day.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=darien-gap-fact-of-the-day">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/darien-gap-fact-of-the-day.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=darien-gap-fact-of-the-day</a></p><p>Votes: 186â¬† 1â¬‡</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/darien-gap-fact-of-the-day.html?commentID=160799624</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/darien-gap-fact-of-the-day.html?commentID=160799624</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[PubbyðŸº]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 02:38:21 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>