<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:09:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on What aspiring economists aren’t being taught by Antiplanner]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Pears compete with apples so there really is no monopoly and it is unlikely that pears use less resources. This would be true of any two goods that someone is considering buying: if someone is debating between the two, the two compete with one another and their prices must reflect that.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793792">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793792</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught</a></p><p>Votes: 352⬆ 14⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793792</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793792</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Antiplanner]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 18:04:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on What aspiring economists aren’t being taught by Duane McMullen]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It's a clever question and Landsburg has a gift for delightful, AI-resistant clever questions.  I get the logic behind arguing that purchasing the pear is the correct answer.  That is exactly how I would answer if I was a grade-hungry student writing a Steve Landsburg mid-term.</p>
<p>However, if was more interested in irritating the professor (more likely the poor TA doing the marking...), this is how I would answer:</p>
<p>The competitive apple producer makes near zero surplus, fully consuming all inputs to generate the apple.  The monopoly pear producer makes 20 cents in profit, consuming only 80 cents in resources to generate the pear.</p>
<p>The resources traded to get the apple or the pear are the same, 100 cents.</p>
<p>For the pear to be the most efficient use of social resources, the 20 cents in profit left with the monopoly pear producer must somehow be used in a way that 'conserves societal resources' better than the near 100% efficiency of resource consumption in producing the apple.</p>
<p>The question does not provide enough information to be able to answer whether or not that 20 cents surplus is used wastefully.  However, the balance of probabilities is that it is used wastefully.</p>
<p>A monopoly provider is likely wasteful to begin with.  A pear produced by a thriving pear producer subject to a competitive market would cost less than 80 cents to produce.  The same inefficient processes that permit the monopoly pear producer to inefficiently produce a pear suggest that 20 cent surplus would also be inefficiently consumed.  Perhaps in successfully lobbying the government to maintain an inefficient monopoly, thereby causing inefficiency to spread in other parts of the economy beyond just pear production.  Perhaps the 20 cent profit is an illusion as the monopoly pear producer has enough political power to extract more than 20 cents from elsewhere in the economy in producing each pear. Perhaps pears in a competitive market pears would consume far less than 80 cents to produce, or could be an extremely profitable export.  Perhaps the 20 cent surplus is extracted as rent by a ruling elite that uses the surplus to fund terrible foreign wars, or to maintain their status as an elite against a more capable and deserving underclass etc etc  Perhaps that same surplus goes to handicapping the apple producers, who otherwise would be even cheaper.</p>
<p>My 100 cents can go to an apple producer who I am confident is consuming resources in the most efficient way, or it can go to a pear producer who I am confident is wastefully consuming resources and getting a surplus to support it continuing to be wasteful.  My utility is the same, whether I buy the apple or the pear.</p>
<p>Resources are socially conserved better when provided to efficient producers rather than inefficient producers.</p>
<p>To choose to allocate resources to an inefficient producer or an efficient producer, when my utility is identical, supports wasteful social consumption.</p>
<p>The most efficient resource consumption choice is to think long term and allocate my resources to the apple.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793818">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793818</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught</a></p><p>Votes: 320⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793818</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793818</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Duane McMullen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 18:25:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on What aspiring economists aren’t being taught by (Not That) Bill O'Reilly]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Antiplanner:</p><blockquote><p>Pears compete with apples so there really is no monopoly and it is unlikely that pears use less resources. This would be true of any two goods that someone is considering buying: if someone is debating between the two, the two compete with one another and their prices must reflect that.</p>
</blockquote><p>Right--it's baked right into the thought experiment that "[y]ou’re hungry and would be equally happy with an apple or a pear," meaning they are perfectly substitutable and therefore in competition. The stipulated fact that pears are monopolized by a single producer doesn't negate the competition.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793800">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793800</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught</a></p><p>Votes: 314⬆ 6⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793800</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793800</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[(Not That) Bill O'Reilly]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 18:14:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on What aspiring economists aren’t being taught by Jimmy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Non-expert here with a re-cap: </p>
<p>(1) Guy asks question: seems interesting to me, but what do I know?<br />
(2) Another guy says that's a bad question. Looks to me like he's giving reasons for that judgment, but are they good? Beats me.<br />
(3) Third guy says: first guy is right, critique is bad. Clearly offers no reasons for that judgment.<br />
(4) Tyler says guy 3 "points out" guy 2 "doesn't have much of an argument." Where did he do that? I don't see it. Is it a Straussian judgment from silence? Is that how such questions are discussed in economics?</p>
<p>This strikes me as strange a very strange post.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793872">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793872</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught</a></p><p>Votes: 280⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793872</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793872</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jimmy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 19:09:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on What aspiring economists aren’t being taught by Hmm]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Antiplanner:</p><blockquote><p>Pears compete with apples so there really is no monopoly and it is unlikely that pears use less resources. This would be true of any two goods that someone is considering buying: if someone is debating between the two, the two compete with one another and their prices must reflect that.</p>
</blockquote><p>Exactly. If the two fruits are substitutes such that I am equally happy with pear and apple then how can pear be a monopoly? Competition between the two fruits exists which means the pear producer necessarily cannot be a price maximizer or setter. If they price at MC=MR and this is above the competitive price of the apple, they will lose business as customers substitute to apples. A true monopoly — for example AT&amp;T in the US before the breakup or water from your local utility — involves a good with imperfect or no substitutability. </p>
<p>So definitionally the pear in the question cannot be produced by a monopoly. </p>
<p>This leads directly to the answer to Tyler’s question: the definition of monopoly.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793819">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793819</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught</a></p><p>Votes: 281⬆ 5⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793819</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793819</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Hmm]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 18:25:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on What aspiring economists aren’t being taught by blue jay]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Tyler, another question: are there any actual monopolies?  IOW, AFAIK, they always have black market competition that has to be supressed, and the cost of that suppression is effectively part of the cost of producing the monopoly product.  No?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793955">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793955</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught</a></p><p>Votes: 272⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793955</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/what-aspiring-economists-arent-being-taught.html?commentID=160793955</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[blue jay]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:18:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by Hazel Meade]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Shark Lasers:</p><blockquote><p>It's interesting how Noah (and, to a lesser extent, Tyler) can get so close on the origins of the vibe shift that they correctly identify that it is a response to Republican messaging, yet not reach the obvious conclusion that it is an orchestrated marketing campaign.</p>
</blockquote><p>Weirdly enough I think Shark Lasers might be right on this. The earlier "vibe shift" was the DNC hitting the brakes on anti-Republican messaging in order to pressure Biden to withdraw from the race. The new "vibe shift" is they are now hitting the gas. And the "wierd" messaging is Harris shoring up the Democratic base by giving them some read meat in the form of insulting Republicans. It's really not aimed at Republicans, it's aimed at making Democratic partisans feel good and rally behind her.<br />
"Vibes" is just a really strange word to use for spin and message control that we're all familiar with. It's not really new or mysterious.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793717">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793717</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463</a></p><p>Votes: 310⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793717</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793717</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Hazel Meade]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 16:42:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by Firebird]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>1: Here we see the difference between a human and a ape. The ape eats the reward, and the human writes a article on how the ape is stupid for eating the reward then proceeds to scroll through tiktok for the immediate dopamine hits.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793780">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793780</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463</a></p><p>Votes: 308⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793780</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793780</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Firebird]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:57:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by PHinton]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Noah writes; "“Normality” and “normalcy”. Those are words that many Americans are desperate to hear after a decade of social media screaming, street battles, riots, protests, coup attempts, domestic terrorism, mass shootings, and assassination attempts.</p>
<p>Noah ignores the fact that this is all tolerated by the left. And even encouraged. Harris celebrated the BLM riots. So did Walz. They both did so under the guise of "justice." Some $4B in losses. </p>
<p>The coup attempt is particularly sad, because it was very tame by BLM standards. However, in order to make a point, the FBI unleased untold resources on finding EVERYONE involved. No matter show small the role. Some have been held for 1300 days without charges or a trial. And this is fair and just to the left. Even when they were the ones that created the environment for the protest to take root by denying NatGaurd resources that everyone in the exec branch wanted (and approved). The cap police wanted them and pleaded for them days ahead of J6. The only people that didn't want the NG was DC Mayor and Pelosi. </p>
<p>Yes, the mass shootings continue unabated in the US. Not because of guns. But because the democrats like Harris refuse to enforce the laws on the books. The laws on the books say a 19 year old with a prior felony caught with an illegal gun should be put away until he's middle aged. But Harris et al can't quite bring themselves to enforce these laws. And so, he's released often without charges (and often with his illegal gun returned). Allowing him to go victimize again and again.</p>
<p>Harris manages by instinct. And unfortunately for us, her instincts are poor. Are very inexperienced. That she believed fanning the flames around George Floyd, but in the end it hurt the poor and black in this country badly. But it made perfect sense to her at the time.</p>
<p>Her instincts have made the world a much more dangerous place than Trump's instincts. The middle east is on fire, our campuses are oozing antisemitism voiced by groups that detest America. Russia and China are testing the waters across the globe. </p>
<p>Noah appears to believe that things can't get much worse. But oh, they can. We just saw how bad things got from Biden's 4 years of being puppeted by a cadre of 30-somethings. There's plenty of room to get even worse. </p>
<p>Does Noah really think 2019 was that bad? % of population working? Inflation? Wars impending? Military readiness? Yes, the press was screaming everything was horrid. And that WAS taxing. But it really wasn't as horrible as today. Now, we have the opposite: The press telling us everything is great. When folks know it's not.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793722">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793722</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463</a></p><p>Votes: 311⬆ 10⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793722</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793722</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[PHinton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 16:46:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by Pepé Silvia]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Hazel Meade:</p><blockquote><p>Weirdly enough I think Shark Lasers might be right on this. The earlier "vibe shift" was the DNC hitting the brakes on anti-Republican messaging in order to pressure Biden to withdraw from the race. The new "vibe shift" is they are now hitting the gas. And the "wierd" messaging is Harris shoring up the Democratic base by giving them some read meat in the form of insulting Republicans. It's really not aimed at Republicans, it's aimed at making Democratic partisans feel good and rally behind her.<br />
"Vibes" is just a really strange word to use for spin and message control that we're all familiar with. It's not really new or mysterious.</p>
</blockquote><p>A couple years ago, Tyler kept repeating variations of "wokeness has peaked, it's now in decline" even while Nancy Pelosi was still taking a knee every time a black dude walked by (more or less, anyway). My impression was that was Tyler's attempt to bootstrap something he wanted to see happen into...actually happening. The "vibe shift" I think was the same thing using slightly different terminology.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793747">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793747</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463</a></p><p>Votes: 300⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793747</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793747</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Pepé Silvia]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:20:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by Tyler Cowen]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Noah Rocks:</p><blockquote><p>This "Adam" script kiddie has been wrecking havoc in the comments section by vote manipulation. It's deprived me a lot of pleasure checking the upvote/downvote counts on my lively contributions, because the upvote count now means nothing.</p>
</blockquote><p>We will be moving to Substack next week. Thanks for joining the conversation!</p>
<p>Tyler</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793773">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793773</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463</a></p><p>Votes: 296⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793773</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793773</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tyler Cowen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:53:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by Tyler Cowen]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to JWatts:</p><blockquote><p>"at 30 liters per second would globally warm Mars by ≳30 kelvin and start to melt the ice."</p>
<p>This is 500 times less than previous estimates using gases. To put it into an easier to grasp number, this translates to about 3 railroad tanker cars worth of particles per hour.</p>
</blockquote><p>One comment per person please.</p>
<p>Tyler</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793685">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793685</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463</a></p><p>Votes: 292⬆ 4⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793685</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793685</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tyler Cowen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 16:14:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by windowpane]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Tyler is teaching youths 18-25, you've also got to  express hope and optimism, even if your internal dialogue is the scribbler's decline and fall.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793960">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793960</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463</a></p><p>Votes: 268⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793960</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793960</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[windowpane]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 23:03:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by GeorgeCo]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I agree with Noah. Tyler, as he points out at the end  of his post, you seem out of touch:</p>
<p>At the same time, though, I think Tyler’s initial post overstated Trump’s personal appeal. The idea that the people of America see him as this cocky funny “winner” type hero, rather than an elderly revenge-obsessed social media addict, feels inaccurate — sure, the former is how his followers see him, but the latter is how a whole lot of normies see him. And this, I think, is what allowed Democrats to shift the vibes back in their direction just by acting normal.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793968">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793968</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463</a></p><p>Votes: 267⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793968</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793968</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[GeorgeCo]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 23:22:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by mkt42]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>"2. New results against HIV.  They seem pretty spectacular."</p>
<p>Spectacular indeed, but aren't these the same results that Tyler linked to in his Friday Assorted Links of June 21, 2024?  Specifically his link #4:<br />
"4. Big news vs. HIV?"</p>
<p>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/friday-assorted-links-474.html</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160794001">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160794001</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463</a></p><p>Votes: 239⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160794001</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160794001</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[mkt42]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 02:30:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by Shark Lasers]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It's interesting how Noah (and, to a lesser extent, Tyler) can get so close on the origins of the vibe shift that they correctly identify that it is a response to Republican messaging, yet not reach the obvious conclusion that it is an orchestrated marketing campaign.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793686">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793686</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463</a></p><p>Votes: 238⬆ 141⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793686</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793686</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Shark Lasers]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 16:15:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Thursday assorted links by Shark Lasers]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to robb:</p><blockquote><p>They *are* pretty weird, though. The messaging isn't free of serious signification.</p>
</blockquote><p>"Weird" as a message from the left is only effective on low-info voters who are only now tuning in to politics.</p>
<p>Late teens in their first Presidential election cycle who grew up around normalized transgenderism, etc. in school and social media is the largest demo that fits this description. It's hard to imagine many of them are true swing voters or are otherwise motivated to go to the polls by this messaging.</p>
<p>On the other hand, "Donald Trump and down-ticket Republicans lost in 2024 because they were just so gosh-darn <i>weird</i>!" sounds like a solid narrative for post-election fortifications by our overlords, pushed out by the Tyler Cowens of the world to placate the midwit class. That would make this nothing more than creating a paper trail.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793754">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793754</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=thursday-assorted-links-463</a></p><p>Votes: 205⬆ 137⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793754</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/thursday-assorted-links-463.html?commentID=160793754</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Shark Lasers]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:24:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on An Economist Solves the Millennium Prize Problems by Sly fox Alex]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Normally, economists are clueless at their public image, but this time, Alex is taking full advantage of it for comedic effect, </p>
<p>It probably would have been not as funny if he had used Thiel paying a billion dollar prize for eternal youth. The punchline about betting the immortality problem 'could be polished off in hardly any time at all. QED.' would fall flat on its face.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793526">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793526</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems</a></p><p>Votes: 352⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793526</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793526</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sly fox Alex]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 11:25:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on An Economist Solves the Millennium Prize Problems by Alexander Kurz]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Andy:</p><blockquote><p>this is a pretty clueless post. Solving one of the millenial problems would give a mathematician instant prestige and recognition (beyond the award money) within the community. There are enough incentives to go around, it's just some problems are hard to crack, the needed techniques to crack it probably haven't been invented yet in some cases, this is like blaming not enough money for not being able to build   airplanes in the renaissance - all the materials and electronics and motors had yet to be invented</p>
</blockquote><p>I thought Alex Tabarrok is making fun of his trade and congratulated him to his self-deprecating, almost English, humour.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793549">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793549</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems</a></p><p>Votes: 324⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793549</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793549</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexander Kurz]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:12:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on An Economist Solves the Millennium Prize Problems by rsm]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>How come Grigory Perelman is immune to incentives?</p>
<p>"In August 2006, Perelman was offered the Fields Medal[1] for "his contributions to geometry and his revolutionary insights into the analytical and geometric structure of the Ricci flow", but he declined the award, stating: "I'm not interested in money or fame; I don't want to be on display like an animal in a zoo."[2] On 22 December 2006, the scientific journal Science recognized Perelman's proof of the Poincaré conjecture as the scientific "Breakthrough of the Year", the first such recognition in the area of mathematics."</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793529">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793529</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems</a></p><p>Votes: 326⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793529</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793529</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[rsm]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 11:32:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on An Economist Solves the Millennium Prize Problems by Bluto]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Alexander Kurz:</p><blockquote><p>I thought Alex Tabarrok is making fun of his trade and congratulated him to his self-deprecating, almost English, humour.</p>
</blockquote><p>Sure, Alex is having a little fun With the post. More importantly, Tyler, how is it that your beloved AI has not helped solve any of these puzzles yet?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793615">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793615</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems</a></p><p>Votes: 310⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793615</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793615</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Bluto]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 14:13:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on An Economist Solves the Millennium Prize Problems by Criens]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Alex‘s posts, even more reliably than Tyler, show what you get if economists don’t take a pause and tink a bit harder about the problem. The prize money is not the only monetary gain someone would get if they solve one of the problems. Also, utility functions are not all quasi - linear, as the author should know</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793538">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793538</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems</a></p><p>Votes: 310⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793538</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793538</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Criens]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 11:54:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on An Economist Solves the Millennium Prize Problems by Phil S.]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Wow.  Whatever prompted Tyler &amp; Alex to close the comments a few days ago, any implemented improvements don't seem to have stuck.  </p>
<p>Comments (and votes, etc.) turning into a garbage dump.</p>
<p>Possibly there's some tie to the election - some entity encouraging (or managing) interference with social media sites with a right-leaning skew?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793673">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793673</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems</a></p><p>Votes: 296⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793673</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/how-to-solve-the-millennium-prize-problems.html?commentID=160793673</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Phil S.]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 15:50:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Walking around Frankfurt by Adam]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>When I visited Frankfurt I stayed at the Holiday Inn. It's a few blocks from the red light district. I was walking to the grocery store to buy some Haribo (Colo-Rado container FTW!) and someone offered me heroin. There are also empty and very large nitrous containers littered along the sidewalk.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793547">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793547</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt</a></p><p>Votes: 312⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793547</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793547</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:10:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Walking around Frankfurt by Steve Sailer]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Adam:</p><blockquote><p>When I visited Frankfurt I stayed at the Holiday Inn. It's a few blocks from the red light district. I was walking to the grocery store to buy some Haribo (Colo-Rado container FTW!) and someone offered me heroin. There are also empty and very large nitrous containers littered along the sidewalk.</p>
</blockquote><p>Hasn't Frankfurt been the leading capitalist city in continental Europe for, I dunno, 1000 years?</p>
<p>Shouldn't Frankfurt by now resemble utopia? </p>
<p>It's like how San Francisco has the most billionaires per capita in America and perhaps in the world, yet it's unpleasant to walk its downtown streets. You can make strong arguments that San Francisco isn't quite as bad as everybody says it is, but shouldn't San Francisco during the AI Boom of 2024 instead be awesome?</p>
<p>Don't economists have a concept called "opportunity cost?"</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793570">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793570</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt</a></p><p>Votes: 302⬆ 15⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793570</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793570</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Sailer]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:51:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Walking around Frankfurt by Jo H]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>A couple of remarks to put the subjective observations about Frankfurt in perspective with the statistics.</p>
<p>Frankfurt is still the third richest city (by PP) in Germany. It is interesting to hear from a US citizen that this doesnt show in the city center. The most noticeable shift has probably been the increase of the amount of office skyscrapers. Median income is ca €55k which is a bit higher than the US average but far away from the richest US cities. </p>
<p>Frankfurt has always been the most international city in Germany after Berlin. In 2022 47% of inhabitants had a migration background (https://statistik.hessen.de/presse/fast-ein-drittel-der-hessischen-bevoelkerung-mit-einwanderungsgeschichte)</p>
<p>The comment that in the 80s the amount of people on the street with a noticeable migration background would probably have been 5% diverges with the statistics. 20% of Frankfurt inhabitants in the 80s had a migration background with the biggest group being Turkish. Maybe the difference is due to that they were not as present in the city centre as they are now.</p>
<p>Frankfurt does not have the highest crime rate per capita of German cities anymore. This title now belongs to Koblenz (https://de.statista.com/statistik/daten/studie/200790/umfrage/gefaehrlichste-staedte-in-deutschland/) Frankfurt still ranks second tand it is something that it has struggled with since a long time.</p>
<p>At the last election (European Parliament) the AFD got 7.7% in Frankfurt. This is far away from the results they achieved in other parts of Germany (Eastern Germany, Ruhrgebiet or Rheinland Pfalz). According to the narrative what is the connection with the rise in right wing voters in Germany? That people from Kaiserslautern or Gelsenkirchen come to visit Frankfurt, see a lot of immigrants and that the city is dirty and then decide to vote AFD to change that?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793478">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793478</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt</a></p><p>Votes: 310⬆ 25⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793478</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793478</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jo H]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 08:13:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Walking around Frankfurt by Clemens]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to PMB:</p><blockquote><p>Frankfurt is one of those cities where you need a local to find the good areas (The opposite of NYC where you need to open your Instagram and you will find thousands of influencers sharing the city's 'secret' gems; you won't find that in unpopular cities like Frankfurt). It has great residential neighbourhoods such as Westend (where you can see the most beautiful university campus), Nordend-West, or the hipster Nordend-Ost. If you stay around the commercial centre or the more party areas of Sachsenhausen, you won't cross by local Germans (they will avoid those areas), only the cited immigrants. I was there for four years between 2014 and 2018 and saw a lot of improvements only during this time, especially at Bahnhofsviertel. There is also the new neighbourhood created around the new ECB building. It was a good city to live in, but it takes some time for you to navigate. Due to the finance industry, I also had a great experience with constant new art exhibitions in the Schirn, the MMKs, and around the Museumsufer.</p>
</blockquote><p>I have lived more than 8 years in Frankfurt and definately share this view. Ultimately, Frankfurt has characteristics that resemble more a small village than a large urban area in the sense that there is not necessarily a strong clustering of certain activities per district as in other larger cities (i.e. an area to go out and party, eating out nicely, ...),at least in my impression, as those activites are more spread out across the city. As such, you have to move around more (as e.g. compared to other large German cities such as Hamburg, Koeln, or Muenich), as well as need to pay more attention to where those places are - definately worth to have a good local guide. </p>
<p>Please keep in mind that crime statistics in Frankfurt have always been high given its role as transportation hub, e.g. any crime related to the airport (50 million passengers a year) shows up in the numerator (crime) but not in the denominator (population).  </p>
<p>Overall, I would argue that Frankfurt has a very high quality of life for residents, since i) it has a good level of public transportation infrastructure, including bike lanes, ii) it is quite "small" yet very international (I would be interested in getting to know Tyler's take on the food scene), iii) has a high GDP p.c. (in the German context) and hosts many large companies, funding cultural events, museums, iv) has due to the aforementioned factors a general open-mindedness (i.e. live and let live) that you might miss in other cities, even though they deem themselves as culturally open (try to walk into a normal bar in Berlin with a suit on ...), which makes the city very enjoyable to live in. The cons Tyler mentions are well-known to local resident who normally avoid passing certain areas at certain times of the day.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793525">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793525</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt</a></p><p>Votes: 269⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793525</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793525</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Clemens]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 11:22:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Walking around Frankfurt by marco]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>TC: "3. It is also striking to me, in a limited number of service sector encounters, that the immigrants with jobs have a “hessisch” accent and Germanic mannerisms...”"</p>
<p>I don't find that striking at all. Many might be second-generation immigrants born and raised in Germany, naturally developing local accents and behaviors. Or am I missing something here?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793485">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793485</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt</a></p><p>Votes: 273⬆ 11⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793485</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793485</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[marco]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 08:36:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Walking around Frankfurt by BC]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Alamo:</p><blockquote><p>Wasn't the Mayor of NYC on the tv screens just a couple of months ago saying things like the migrant crisis was going to "destroy NYC", "we have no more room", "enough is enough", and so on?</p>
<p>Didn't officials in cities like Chicago say similar things?</p>
<p>Didn't we have anti-illegal migrant protests in Staten Island and the Bronx just a few months ago?</p>
<p>All this after DeSantis and Abbott send just a few planes with illegal immigrants to those blue cities.</p>
<p>The distinction between legal and illegal immigrant, and the type of illegal immigrant, is absolutely fundamental to understand public perceptions of immigration in the US - but this blog, and the type of people who read/comment on it are completely oblivious to that distinction (and likely find it quite gauche).</p>
</blockquote><p>I think Tyler is talking about legal immigrants in Frankfurt.  I thought AfD and much of the anti-immigrant sentiment in Europe is directed towards legal immigrants, particularly Muslim legal immigrants.  In the US, much of the opposition is directed towards Christian immigration, both legal and illegal, across the Southern Border.  Indeed, some people seem completely "oblivious" to distinctions...</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793607">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793607</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt</a></p><p>Votes: 257⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793607</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793607</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[BC]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 13:52:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Walking around Frankfurt by M]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>TC: "<i>But now it seems decidedly poorer</i>"</p>
<p>I wonder how much we have induced biases on this topic. </p>
<p>I was watching some UK TV yesterday, covering collectively some periods spanning the 1970s up to 1997. According to some measures 1997 was a relative higher point in UK:US GDP PPP parity (around 81%, about the level it would stay until the peak), while back in 1973 or today its about 73% (World Bank Constant 2021 for post 1990, Maddison Project/PWT for back-projection beyond 1990). </p>
<p>But the perception of a change in relative wealth was surprisingly not very salient to me, and much more salient was how cultures had changed or remained constant across the time series. Not that my perceptions were inverse or opposed to the numbers, just it didn't seem obvious to me that the numbers were evident in what I was seeing. (The relative quality of people's clothes, the quality of government services, the quality of the other services and goods they were consuming on screen etc).</p>
<p>So I wonder how much noticing changes can because we can be primed by a statistic to expect a change? </p>
<p>When it was 2019, and Germany had, by the numbers, been on a pretty constant growth convergence upwards towards the United States (Germany 1984 - 73% of US; Germany 2019 - 89% of US; Maddison/PWT and WB 2021 KD), would we have been primed to perceive that Frankfurt was relatively richer?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793465">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793465</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt</a></p><p>Votes: 265⬆ 11⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793465</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793465</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[M]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 07:48:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Walking around Frankfurt by Peter Akuleyev]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>“ It is also striking to me, in a limited number of service sector encounters, that the immigrants with jobs have a “hessisch” accent and Germanic mannerisms”</p>
<p>Is Tyler’s German really good enough to distinguish local accents?  As a fluent German speaker myself I find this statement pretty suspect. Frankfurt is the sort of city where even most native Germans don’t/can’t speak the traditional dialect. Maybe some of the more integrated immigrants have absorbed some local phonetical features but I doubt they sound particularly “Hessisch” to the few remaining old Frankfurters left.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793748">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793748</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt</a></p><p>Votes: 247⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793748</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793748</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Peter Akuleyev]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:20:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Walking around Frankfurt by Simon K]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>OK, time to bail. I've read MR for well over a decade, even though Tyler's politics are diametrically opposed to mine. In fact, specifically *because* Tyler's politics are diametrically opposed to mine, because it's healthy to read opinions that challenge your own.</p>
<p>But the line about “potentially objectionable immigrants”  just goes too far for me. We get it, you don't like brown people (at least not where you expect to find white people - you love to show off about how much you enjoy travelling to other countries to be condescending on what you consider their own turf).</p>
<p>It's time for me to find a right-wing commentator who can express sensible economic and political opinions that I disagree with without also being a massive racist.</p>
<p>(What's that? Yes, I did read the line about "at least by the standards of anti-immigrant Germans". No, there's nothing wrong with my reading comprehension. Yes, I get that Tyler is trying to say that it's not him who holds those views, he's just trying to say what other people might think. No, I don't buy it for a minute.)</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793701">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793701</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt</a></p><p>Votes: 251⬆ 5⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793701</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793701</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Simon K]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 16:28:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Walking around Frankfurt by Andreas]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Aldo Compagnoni:</p><blockquote><p>"if you wish to understand the popularity of AfD" which is most popular in rural Saxony, then go to Frankfurt.</p>
<p>I am not sure whether I am missing context, or whether your logic is wrong?</p>
</blockquote><p>Tyler clearly has point and I hate to admit it, displays a good understanding of Germany in this regard. It remains true that the AfD is strongest in the eastern states (i.e. Thüringen, Sachsen, Brandenburg). But dont deceive yourself, even in Hessen there is considerable support if you leave Frankfurt (e.g. AfD is the strongest party in the Wetteraukreis bordering Frankfurt). Anyways, Frankfurt is ripe with MENAPT immigrants that show little to no integrationand, tend to be pretty violent and are living on social benefits. Their unchecked immigration is the main reason for the AfD‘s ascendancy. People are afraid that Germany is turning into a third world shithole where long term Sharia rule will be established. That East Germans are more supportive of the AfD has a simple reason, they are less susceptible  to the propaganda of the state media (Öffentlicher Rundfunk) that either outright denies problems with criminal MENAPT immigrants or frames these problems as far right conspiracy theories. From a US perspective it is probably pretty hard to understand that the main objective of many immigrants that consecutive left wing governments have let in, is to enslave the native population and establish a theocracy.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793953">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793953</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=walking-around-frankfurt</a></p><p>Votes: 179⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793953</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/walking-around-frankfurt.html?commentID=160793953</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Andreas]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:07:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Life in Belarus update (from my email, from anonymous) by NK]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Only an economist would think this is a positive development. It is not.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793440">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793440</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous</a></p><p>Votes: 326⬆ 8⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793440</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793440</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[NK]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 05:27:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Life in Belarus update (from my email, from anonymous) by Crikey]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Markets are great at resolving supply issues.  They do this through prices.  Belarus and Russia are paying a high price for products from China.  (And other countries.)   If they were getting a good deal from China, Russia would have more new Chinese tires on their trucks and more Chinese made trucks than they do.</p>
<p>In other words, sanctions have reduced the amount of resources available to the Russian Federation.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793441">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793441</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous</a></p><p>Votes: 308⬆ 6⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793441</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793441</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Crikey]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 05:38:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Life in Belarus update (from my email, from anonymous) by Crikey]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to SpeculativeDiction:</p><blockquote><p>We don't know that about prices. China is known for engaging in dumping-like behaviour with their exports which is very controversial atm but I doubt Minsk/Russia care too much.</p>
<p>China is the largest manufacturer in the world by a longshot and manufactures more than the USA+EU+Japan+UK combined. The EU and Japan might keep some manufacturing share but USA/UK/CAN/AUS/NZ with their open capital markets will continue to have their share hammered as they import the consequences of Chinese policies due to open capital markets. The USA is particularly screwed as the global reserve currency they basically cannot keep their exports competitive on a global scale.</p>
<p>This is all very worrying from a geopolitical perspective as the Anglosphere is the core linchpin on which the liberal order rests but I doubt the NYC-LDN financial establishment will give up the wealth and privileges running the world's finances give them. And the whole Anglosphere is dealing with housing problems which foreign capital flight has played a large part in creating.</p>
<p>Reading Michael Pettis on this subject is very enlightening, he maps out the issues very well.</p>
</blockquote><p>Since the invasion of Ukraine, Russia's exports of oil to China are up by around half.  Gas is up maybe 50%.  Coal is dramatically up.  All discounted compared to international prices.  So Russia is definitely paying for Chinese imports.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793447">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793447</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous</a></p><p>Votes: 293⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793447</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793447</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Crikey]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 06:35:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Life in Belarus update (from my email, from anonymous) by RAD]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to NK:</p><blockquote><p>Only an economist would think this is a positive development. It is not.</p>
</blockquote><p>Hmmmm... I seem to lack the ability to suss out Tyler's thoughts based on his contribution, the title: "Life in Belarus". </p>
<p>Personally, I'm surprised to hear about the extensive influence of China in Belarus before hearing about it in Moscow. Cold War 2.0 is unfortunately very real, pitting the core CRINKs (China, Russia, Iran, and North Korea) and the illiberal Asian nation-states within their sphere of influence against America and her alliance of Orderly Liberal Meritocracies. The CCP can not be happy about Putin forcing their hand. The Russian execution of Aleksandr Dugin's <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foundations_of_Geopolitics" rel="nofollow ugc"> playbook may not have gone according to plan but Putin is sticking to the strategy:</p>
<blockquote><p>Outside of Ukraine and Georgia, military operations play a relatively minor role except for the military intelligence operations Dugin calls "special military operations". The textbook advocates a sophisticated program of subversion, destabilization, and disinformation spearheaded by the Russian secret services. The operations should be assisted by a tough, hard-headed utilization of Russia's gas, oil, and natural resources to bully and pressure other countries. The book states that "the maximum task [of the future] is the 'Finlandization' of all of Europe".</p></blockquote>
<p>My question is how many anti-<b>MR</b> commenters are CRINK agents vs true-blue neoreactionaries? </p>
<p>May you live in interesting times :-(</a></p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793530">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793530</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous</a></p><p>Votes: 287⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793530</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793530</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[RAD]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 11:43:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Life in Belarus update (from my email, from anonymous) by Old Programmer]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Do you think the e-mail from Belarus was read by a government employee before or after it went to Tyler?  Do you think the author of the e-mail thinks it could or would be read by someone in government?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793522">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793522</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous</a></p><p>Votes: 282⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793522</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793522</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Old Programmer]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 11:09:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Life in Belarus update (from my email, from anonymous) by mikeInThe716]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to mikeInThe716:</p><blockquote><p>Props to Tyler for visiting Minsk.</p>
<p>I'm concerned. </p>
<p>Did Tyler consider the risk of a "Gershkovich" type event for himself?   </p>
<p>Or is Tyler and his non-MSM platform(s) not that well known? </p>
<p>In my world, it seems like a semi (ish) famous classical liberal economist would be worth more than a standard leftoid from the WSJ for trading...</p>
<p> Is Putin slipping?</p>
</blockquote><p>I'm a moron.<br />
The account is from Tyler's email.  Tyler didn't visit.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793605">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793605</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous</a></p><p>Votes: 278⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793605</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793605</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[mikeInThe716]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 13:40:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Life in Belarus update (from my email, from anonymous) by Bryan W]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to NK:</p><blockquote><p>Only an economist would think this is a positive development. It is not.</p>
</blockquote><p>Um... I don't know what has gotten into Tyler. I keep hoping Tyler would write some patriotic blog posts that cheer for America, like the kind I see from Noah Smith, BAP, and others. And my hope keeps getting thwarted. Why? What's the mental hurdle that needs clearing? Can we the MR commentariat helps Tyler clear that? I hate to say it, but I think the root cause is that Tyler has a mistaken elitist notion that to write such content would not be "scholarly" or would be some form of "intellectual prostitution". This I suspect is the chief mental hurdle. It's why Tyler cannot give us Noah or BAP style content, at least not layered in three layers of Straussian irony. To which I say, Tyler, that even if, for the size of argument, you are right, you will get over it, like a new arrival at your local spa place gets over it. We were all shy at one point, totally understandable. What's less understandable is not even making the minimum of effort to clear the mental hurdle and bring your readers the content they demand. Less and less acceptable every single day.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793484">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793484</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous</a></p><p>Votes: 289⬆ 11⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793484</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793484</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Bryan W]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 08:28:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Life in Belarus update (from my email, from anonymous) by mikeInThe716]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Props to Tyler for visiting Minsk.</p>
<p>I'm concerned. </p>
<p>Did Tyler consider the risk of a "Gershkovich" type event for himself?   </p>
<p>Or is Tyler and his non-MSM platform(s) not that well known? </p>
<p>In my world, it seems like a semi (ish) famous classical liberal economist would be worth more than a standard leftoid from the WSJ for trading...</p>
<p> Is Putin slipping?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793561">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793561</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous</a></p><p>Votes: 278⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793561</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793561</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[mikeInThe716]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:34:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Life in Belarus update (from my email, from anonymous) by Falstaff]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Tired: Tyler Cowen, neoliberalism<br />
Wired: John von Neumann, preemptive nuclear strikes</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793434">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793434</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous</a></p><p>Votes: 280⬆ 7⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793434</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793434</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Falstaff]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 04:57:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Life in Belarus update (from my email, from anonymous) by Niko Davor]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to NK:</p><blockquote><p>Only an economist would think this is a positive development. It is not.</p>
</blockquote><p>Tyler is reporting with disappointment that the US-led efforts to cripple the economies of Russia + Belarus aren't working and those economies are proving more resilient and dynamic than expected. I'm surprised you had the opposite interpretation.</p>
<p>A free trade advocate would say, let the people of Belarus work and trade and enjoy a nice standard of living. The US elites are trying to crush the economies of their geopolitical rivals and that involves blocking peaceful economic trade. Tyler supports crushing the economies of Russia + Belarus, but is less supportive of doing that to China; he opposed sanctions against Chinese cars, for example. Tyler also dishonestly portrays the free trade debate as the wise academic economists versus the idiotic populist right. Instead, it's a bipartisan US foreign policy elite driving anti-free-trade policy, and the public, both on the left and right, are clueless about sanctions and US efforts to crush the economies of geopolitical rivals.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793643">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793643</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous</a></p><p>Votes: 262⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793643</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793643</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Niko Davor]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 15:09:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Life in Belarus update (from my email, from anonymous) by Niko Davor]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Restless carrot:</p><blockquote><p>It's positive in the sense that today the world is more multipolar which increases institutional competition and therefore institutional quality.</p>
<p>It's only bad for those who have an irrational fetish for American unipolarity. It's irrational because it does not benefit the US's population in general: it's better for average American taxpayer that Washington's action set is strictly constrained by rival powers.</p>
<p>However, an issue might arise if China gets too dominant and it becomes a institutional monopolist dictating the institutions for the whole planet. That is, if China becomes powerful enough to become a new Rome.</p>
</blockquote><p>You present a good argument for multipolarity: it breaks the unipolar monopoly on world government, and competition may lead to increased institutional/government quality. Would multipolarity bring more war and military conflict? I don't know.</p>
<p>The people who run US government, including Tyler, are overwhelmingly in favor of US-led unipolarity, they are willing to use military force to fight against multipolarity, and they are basically hiding this from the public rather than trying to debate this position publicly.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793845">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793845</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous</a></p><p>Votes: 202⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793845</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/life-in-belarus-update-from-my-email-from-anonymous.html?commentID=160793845</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Niko Davor]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 18:53:24 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>