<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 10:09:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The decline in retail sales jobs by Sure]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This is part of why I wonder if this time really will be different for AI. I spend a lot of my time with the bottom half of the distribution (and take your pick for IQ, morals, religious praxis, education, SES, or most anything else, the folks who are incarcerated tend to be in the bottom half) and I absolutely do wonder what a lot of these folks can do productively. </p>
<p>We have always been able to order stuff by submitting forms, but retail jobs had folks who could manipulate physical objects, problem shoot, and overall make the purchasing experience more pleasant and frictionless while making it harder for theft and fraud to take too much of a bite. </p>
<p>Yet a lot of that seems heavily degraded. It is simply too easy to order the exact same thing from Amazon for a huge number of retailers. Robots than can handle delicate goods already exist and the question is when, not if, somebody has them manage inventory and checkouts. While there are a few idiots who are quite personable, in general folks from the bottom half of the distribution are not particularly pleasant for other folks to deal with. </p>
<p>And even if you had a good way to rule out criminals taking jobs just to rob the store ... corporations are overwhelmingly against employees doing most anything to confront criminals. And if anything, technology is going to make it even easier to lock away high theft items with some form of facial recognition software that only opens the case when they can ID you and refuse repeat shoplifters. </p>
<p>Yeah people hate the uncanny valley and dislike even the idea of not being worth human interaction ... but realistically how many jobs can retail sustain if you can have an AI handle 80% of the customer interactions and remote presence for another 15% and just write-off the last 5% to boutique firms or a tiny number of more highly remunerated folks who actually have skills beyond the bottom half?</p>
<p>Manufacturing jobs are a terrible fit - modern equipment is way too expensive and regardless of the regs, companies do not want idiots who will slow production with safety violations. </p>
<p>Medicine is terrible because even the folks who wipe bums all day are supposed to be able to do CPR, need background checks to deal with vulnerable groups (e.g. children, seniors), and are increasingly getting tasked with working with complex equipment (e.g. telesitters). Not to mention the mountains of patience needed to handle folks with no functional memory, psychiatric disorders, or just plain unpleasantness. </p>
<p>Education, ehh pretty much the same thing. Folks at the bottom teach all the wrong habits and with ever fewer kids, education is unlikely to be a growth industry. </p>
<p>Agriculture already employs very few people and even if that number rebounds, everything is getting expensive. Machinery is blindingly expensive. Regulation violations can cost you market access (e.g. somebody fails to clean feces off udders and you can lose days worth of milk as unsaleable) and farms with violations get dropped to the cheapest commodity status. </p>
<p>Mining and resource extraction, ehh does not look great as again, the machinery keeps getting more expensive and complicated. Safety - be it government regs, downtime minimization (at least from my side, serious workplace accidents result in huge work stoppages), or lawsuit risk ... people who cannot follow the rules are not going to be welcome on mining sites. And that is before we consider the issues with drug use. </p>
<p>And before anyone wants to tell me about comparative advantage, I just want to see your actual math for how that works out with minimum wages, required benefits, and compliance costs. </p>
<p>Heck, even prostitution seems like it would not be too viable as VR/Only Fans/AI/robotics are going to eat heavily into the market for simple physical stimulation. And for the folks who want a human interaction beyond a decent chatbot ... I am not seeing this being a viable option for people with terrible people skills, particularly with the males. </p>
<p>Maybe the wealthy will like having a bunch of servants just for the status signaling, but my guess is that the wealthy will continue to grow up with ever less exposure to actually moronic people and it just isn't worth much to have a butler who sounds annoying, cannot master the social graces, and can be signaled about as well by buying a name-brand custom AI assistant and gold plating the toilet. </p>
<p>Sales, the arts, law enforcement, firefighting ... they all are requiring ever more skill to do anything of note. </p>
<p>Maybe somebody has a plan for what a 33-year-old with an 85 IQ, a felony conviction for theft, and a penchant for sexual harassment should do in the coming new order ... but damned if I do. And I watch guys like him walk out of incarceration every week. </p>
<p>I mean right now the highest success options I know for placement are construction labor and landscaping. But I am highly doubtful that those will be there if retail falls apart and the functional folks can work with robots to do the heavy lifting. </p>
<p>And the longest run scales have been seeing ever fewer hours worked with ever lower labor force participation for men. So maybe the present trend just accelerates into a bunch of guys doing nothing and the government paying them off with video games, booze, weed, and hookers in some (indirect) fashion?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/the-decline-in-retail-sales-jobs.html?commentID=160820335">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/the-decline-in-retail-sales-jobs.html?commentID=160820335</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/the-decline-in-retail-sales-jobs.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-decline-in-retail-sales-jobs">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/the-decline-in-retail-sales-jobs.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-decline-in-retail-sales-jobs</a></p><p>Votes: 56⬆ 8⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/the-decline-in-retail-sales-jobs.html?commentID=160820335</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/the-decline-in-retail-sales-jobs.html?commentID=160820335</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sure]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 15:26:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>