<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 10:06:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Don’t bother learning about this one, unless you already know what I am talking about by Susan D Einbinder]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As the current Chair of an IRB (and a member of one or another for 20 years), technically, review is only required if the study has a few sources of federal funding BUT our mandate is quite simple:  Protect participants.  This study exposes the names of people competing for jobs, which might - might - put one or more of them at risk at their current jobs or by disclosing information that would otherwise remain private.  This means the study has to be reviewed by the IRB.  Not sure it would fly, either ....</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760692">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760692</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about</a></p><p>Votes: 109⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760692</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760692</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Susan D Einbinder]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 22:25:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Don’t bother learning about this one, unless you already know what I am talking about by superdestroyer]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Ricardo:</p><blockquote><p>I will disregard the title because I wasn't aware of this particular case but I do know a few things about IRBs.</p>
<p>Based on current standards, I don't see the argument for not approving the experiment. Is there genuine uncertainty over whether having your paper tweeted out by a prominent account helps you on the job market? Maybe not, but the authors would have had to do their literature review and justify why this is a legitimate research question. If their arguments were flawed, someone should explain why.</p>
<p>Second, is a scarce resource involved in the experiment? You could dispute this but I think it is intuitive that attention on social media is a bit of a scarce resource. If a prominent Twitter account tweets out links to 500+ papers, the message gets diluted compared to if it only tweets out ~250. If there is a scarce resource that is probably being somewhat arbitrarily and unfairly distributed in the real-world and, given the research question above, that is most of what you need to pass IRB.</p>
<p>Informed consent is typically not demanded in real-world experiments like this where you are not surveying people or bringing them into a laboratory setting.</p>
<p>However, there is an entirely separate <b>professional ethics</b> at stake that is beyond the scope of what IRBs deal with. Should there be a code of conduct among economists that they should publicly promote academic work in an unbiased manner and should have no ulterior motives when they do so? If so, then this experiment would violate that code. If not, it just becomes a reputational thing. If people know that the next time you promote a certain paper it may be because you are running an RCT or doing something other than strictly promoting all of the high-quality work you are coming across, people may listen to your recommendations less.</p>
</blockquote><p>Social science research goes through IRB all of the time.  This type of research would probably fly through with expedited review due to minimal risk.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760504">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760504</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about</a></p><p>Votes: 158⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760504</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760504</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[superdestroyer]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 12:48:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The death of the AI safety movement? by RAD]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As of May, 2024:<br />
p(DOOM) -&gt; zero<br />
QED</p>
<p>The core DOOMer assumption was that a misaligned Artificial Super Intelligence (ASI) would crush humanity like ants after a fast-takeoff FOOM event; the AI Singularity. </p>
<p>These Natural Language Machines are not AGI, never mind ASI, the take-off is slow, and the energy/compute infrastructure looks to be constrained by the pace and performance of human managed mega-projects. Always check your assumptions. </p>
<p>Having said that, these Natural Language Machines are powerful tools posed to unlock the vast amount of unstructured data previously opaque to software. The question is how deep the disruption will be. The range seems to be from a fourth pillar in the web/mobile/cloud revolution to a new AI-driven digital revolution that dwarfs the previous 30-year epoch.</p>
<p>Multi-step agents working on long time horizons seem to be on the cusp of becoming mainstream. Self-iterating LLM agents may accelerate the pace of innovation and adoption. May you live in interesting times.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760461">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760461</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement</a></p><p>Votes: 172⬆ 7⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760461</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760461</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[RAD]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 08:06:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The death of the AI safety movement? by M]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>TC: <i>"Lawmakers seem to understand that they would rather face the risks of US-based AI systems than have to contend with Chinese developments without a US counterweight. The early history of Covid, when the Chinese government behaved recklessly and nontransparently, has driven this realization home."</i></p>
<p>It's not necessarily the only reasoning though. If China is threatening to the US, it might be *more* important that the US not commit acts of self-harm, via "unsafe AI", that weaken it in the face of Chinese competition?</p>
<p>It's entirely possible that less "safe AI" by US -&gt; more fraud (including academic fraud that weakens the standing of Western science), more crime, more mental health disorders and more impenetrable and complex financial engineering in the US -&gt; US is relatively weakened to China.</p>
<p>TC perhaps thinks about the US's strength in the same way that US's frontier companies think about it; in terms of their product sophistication and their valuations and the total value of the publicly traded stock market and so on. But it's possible that these can increase up while their products weaken US society and its economy. The Magnificent Seven are not America. Startups are not America.</p>
<p>On balance I'm still optimistic about these technologies (they offer the prospect of release from the most repetitive and poorly paid parts of the service economy, and that's the least of it). But all possibilities should be considered. It's entirely possible that the tortoises beat the hare here.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760470">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760470</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement</a></p><p>Votes: 166⬆ 4⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760470</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760470</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[M]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 09:19:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The death of the AI safety movement? by JustAnotherScientist]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>AI safety?  Eh.  Lots of things aren't safe.  Danger is the spice of life.</p>
<p>AI Notkilleveryoneism?  That one I'm firmly behind.  With most things I don't worry about being replaced as the smartest species on the planet.  </p>
<p>AI is awesome, and I use it every day in my work.  It frees my marginal hour to work on more important things the AI can't help with... yet.  But I only slightly worry that the AI will eventually leave me with no margin to move to.  That would be a weird world, but I can deal with weird.</p>
<p>What worries me is that the simplest way to do a job better is to get more resources to do it.  Even without a foom, when we set the AI a goal of "make money", we see naturally in humans that this leads to a push to gather more power to further the goal.</p>
<p>That works OK for humans, and yes I'm OK with capitalism.  But I'm that future world, a human making decisions becomes a disadvantage.  The equilibrium looks like everyone puts more and more control in the AI's digital hands. </p>
<p>In that equilibrium the competitive race will be to put more and more computer and energy in your AI's control. US, China, OpenAI, whomever. </p>
<p>If humanity's capabilities are not a special ceiling level on the exponential scaling laws, and I see no reason to believe we are, we become a lot less relevant.  Personally, I like driving the future, but maybe a post scarcity abundant Utopia less thataway.  I am skeptical, but whatever. </p>
<p>But whether you call it foom, picture Skynet raining fire, imagine curious Yellow spreading -- the equilibrium looks like a technology with exponential scaling laws stuck on a loop of runaway growth locked in by lack of coordination... even if (when) most humans don't want that.</p>
<p>And ultimately, that system has a poorly understood objective function while we increasingly arrive to give it agency to take it's own actions and set it's own sub goals. </p>
<p>What do we do if a system like that decides our atoms could be used better for something else?</p>
<p>I don't think this movement has peaked.  I do think it has grown quite rapidly, but I think it will continue to grow each time something sufficiently unexpected jolts the zeitgeist beyond the usual boiling frog background tempo.  Compute limits driving reporting at the frontier level are a light touch and an elegant solution; 10^26 is a generous runway.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760508">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760508</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement</a></p><p>Votes: 157⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760508</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760508</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[JustAnotherScientist]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 13:10:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The death of the AI safety movement? by MC]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Comments of this post that were critical were deleted. I can't say for sure it was by TC but they made some points I think should be here so I will try to reiterate them (probably poorly). </p>
<p>TC's bias on this subject is pretty clear. He is cherry picking examples and nowhere is there mention of incidents on MR of Jan Leike's resignation. (he just gestures broadly to everything and calls it 'safetyism').</p>
<p>TC doesn't mention or elaborate on the actual arguments of 'doomers'. He just disparagingly calls them 'worriers' and is using his site to declare preemptive victory in order to hurt morale and generally gaslight people who are concerned about this technology.</p>
<p>The fact that TC is this biased on this subject, having for years seemed to be level headed and fair-minded casts doubts on his past musings.</p>
<p>The fact that the earliest critical comments (that had the most upvotes btw) on this post are nowhere to be seen only strengthen the points laid out in them imo.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760660">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760660</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement</a></p><p>Votes: 136⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760660</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760660</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[MC]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 20:26:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on How important is “the scientific method”? by How about favoring strict definitions first?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>First, discoveries need not use anything at all, much less the scientific method, to be originated, Such as someone like Einstein performing his thought experiments . However, confirming those discoveries most definitely used the scientific method in all its rigorous glory.</p>
<p>"A hallmark of Albert Einstein's career was his use of visualized thought experiments as a fundamental tool for understanding physical issues and for elucidating his concepts to others. Einstein's thought experiments took diverse forms. In his youth, he mentally chased beams of light. For special relativity, he employed moving trains and flashes of lightning to explain his most penetrating insights. For general relativity, he considered a person falling off a roof, accelerating elevators, blind beetles crawling on curved surfaces and the like. "</p>
<p>"A thought experiment is a logical argument or mental model cast within the context of an imaginary (hypothetical or even counterfactual) scenario. A scientific thought experiment, in particular, may examine the implications of a theory, law, or set of principles with the aid of fictive and/or natural particulars (demons sorting molecules, cats whose lives hinge upon a radioactive disintegration, men in enclosed elevators) in an idealized environment (massless trapdoors, absence of friction). They describe experiments that, except for some specific and necessary idealizations, could conceivably be performed in the real world.</p>
<p>As opposed to physical experiments, thought experiments do not report new empirical data."</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?commentID=160760302">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?commentID=160760302</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-important-is-the-scientific-method">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-important-is-the-scientific-method</a></p><p>Votes: 234⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?commentID=160760302</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?commentID=160760302</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[How about favoring strict definitions first?]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 18:30:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on How important is “the scientific method”? by Jeremy Fox]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Leaving aside any other issues with the paper, framing the result as an argument for methodological pluralism is a little odd. "75% of Nobel Prize winners recommend the scientific method" seems like a pretty good advertisement for the scientific method! It's quite close to those old ads for Trident sugar-free gum, that claimed Trident was recommended by "four out of five dentists."</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?commentID=160760359">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?commentID=160760359</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-important-is-the-scientific-method">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-important-is-the-scientific-method</a></p><p>Votes: 184⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?commentID=160760359</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?commentID=160760359</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremy Fox]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 20:47:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on How important is “the scientific method”? by Incognito]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Example, Female Sports Competition events are over because any Male can have his junk altered and compete. Yet these Males are not carrying  Life within their bodies, besides that little sack they just had removed.<br />
The Burden that women carry.<br />
Tossed to the rocks.<br />
And not allowing them to compete against their own gender.<br />
It's f n bananas<br />
And not funny in anyway<br />
Women have this burden and gift<br />
of giving birth and nurturing our future<br />
and you've just taken away<br />
a way to compete<br />
with their like kind/gender<br />
when they're youngins?<br />
And it ain't about bigtime winning<br />
It's about competition and excelling when you're young<br />
Bringing about fair competition and finding abilities you didn't know you had.<br />
And fond memories, from winning and losing.<br />
Amongst Sport competitions of your own Sex.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?commentID=160760369">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?commentID=160760369</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-important-is-the-scientific-method">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-important-is-the-scientific-method</a></p><p>Votes: 164⬆ 16⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?commentID=160760369</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/how-important-is-the-scientific-method.html?commentID=160760369</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Incognito]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 21:24:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Wednesday assorted links by The Midnight Narwhals with Bacon]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Blackthorne:</p><blockquote><p>Re 1: I imagine the spatial distribution of native americans is playing a role here. They have a much higher suicide rate and make up a larger % of the population in many of those states (https://worldpopulationreview.com/state-rankings/native-american-population). Still doesn't seem like it explains everything</p>
</blockquote><p>This. You see the same thing among native populations in Alaska, Greenland, and the Northern Territories.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?commentID=160760234">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?commentID=160760234</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=wednesday-assorted-links-454">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=wednesday-assorted-links-454</a></p><p>Votes: 188⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?commentID=160760234</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?commentID=160760234</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Midnight Narwhals with Bacon]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 16:30:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Wednesday assorted links by No slippery slopes in Germany]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to steve:</p><blockquote><p>#2- In the case of unavoidable harm the Swedes seem to have a preference for preserving the life of the pedestrian over the car passengers. First, I wonder if Americans would survey the same way. Second, will the purchasers of self driving cars be happy if they know the algorithm favors the pedestrian?</p>
<p>Steve</p>
</blockquote><p>Of course they do. Europeans consider walking (and in a number of countries, bicycling) in their neighborhoods a normal activity, from young children to the elderly. Car driving is a relatively new social change in societies that were exclusively pedestrian (except for a few horses) a century and a half ago. America is a true outlier in this regard, for a variety of reasons.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?commentID=160760254">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?commentID=160760254</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=wednesday-assorted-links-454">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=wednesday-assorted-links-454</a></p><p>Votes: 188⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?commentID=160760254</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?commentID=160760254</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[No slippery slopes in Germany]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 17:06:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Wednesday assorted links by Peter]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to rsm:</p><blockquote><p>If you add suicide by cop, does New York rise to the top?</p>
</blockquote><p>The classic NYC suicide method is 12-9'ing, namely taking a swan dive in front of an oncoming subway train.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?commentID=160760295">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?commentID=160760295</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=wednesday-assorted-links-454">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=wednesday-assorted-links-454</a></p><p>Votes: 185⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?commentID=160760295</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/wednesday-assorted-links-454.html?commentID=160760295</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Peter]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 18:20:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The Left on FDA Peer Approval by blue jay]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Naveen K:</p><blockquote><p>I had the same question on why some company won't evergreen ambroxol so I asked GPT-4:</p>
<p>Challenges and Considerations<br />
Cost of Development and Approval: The process of modifying the drug and conducting the necessary clinical trials is expensive and time-consuming. For a generic drug like ambroxol, the return on investment might be questionable unless the new version offers significant advantages over the original.</p>
<p>Market Competition: There are already several mucolytic agents available in the U.S. market. Introducing a slightly modified version of ambroxol might not be enough to guarantee substantial market share, especially if healthcare providers and patients are already satisfied with existing treatments.</p>
<p>Regulatory Hurdles: The FDA has stringent requirements for approving new drugs or modified versions of existing drugs. The company would need to demonstrate that the new version is safe and effective, which requires robust clinical data. The FDA might not grant approval if the modifications are deemed too minor or if the benefits over the original are not clear.</p>
<p>Profitability Concerns: Since ambroxol is cheap and widely available as a generic in other markets, pricing the new version competitively while recouping development costs could be challenging.</p>
</blockquote><p>Keeping in mind, of course, that GPT-4 makes up bullshit all the time and is generally unreliable.  </p>
<p>But it's interesting that it says "There are already several mucolytic agents available in the U.S. market. "  Is that true?  If so...why do we have this column?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?commentID=160760047">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?commentID=160760047</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-left-on-fda-peer-approval">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-left-on-fda-peer-approval</a></p><p>Votes: 180⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?commentID=160760047</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?commentID=160760047</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[blue jay]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 12:01:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The Left on FDA Peer Approval by blue jay]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Luka:</p><blockquote><p>The left are really weird when it comes to what kind of substances they think we should and should not be allowed to use. Some want to legalize all recreational drugs, even heroin. The logic tends to be an emphasis on our personal freedom and the racist harm of the drug war. At the same time they hate modern medicine and "Big Pharma" (except COVID-19 vaccines) and won't speed up approval of something as banal as sunscreens already legal in other rich nations. There is a strong tendency to want to regulate new drugs, medicines, and even food for our "safety" or even ban them. They're willing to trust adults to take meth but not necessarily a novel new pain or heart medication because it <i>might</i> be dangerous. </p>
<p>Before anyone jumps in with a "What about the Republicans????", I know they have their own set of problems, I'm just trying to figure out leftist logic on this. What exactly are their priorities? It seems to follow Bryan Caplan's belief that the left is basically motivated by a distaste for markets. They just don't like the idea of a corporation creating new pharmaceuticals and making money off of it.</p>
</blockquote><p>"They just don't like the idea of a [corporation, company or person] creating [anything] and making money off of it."</p>
<p>They don't like profit, but they especially don't like anything that would make one [person, corporation] earn more than another, bcz that shatters the belief that we're all just different color M&amp;Ms and that blue, green red and yellow must be distributed proportionally across the cookie according to some natural law.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?commentID=160760041">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?commentID=160760041</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-left-on-fda-peer-approval">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-left-on-fda-peer-approval</a></p><p>Votes: 197⬆ 21⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?commentID=160760041</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?commentID=160760041</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[blue jay]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 11:53:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The Left on FDA Peer Approval by blue jay]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Naveen K:</p><blockquote><p>Alex already mentions the chemical principle is entirely different. Ambroxol reduces mucus viscosity and increases surfactant production, while acetylcysteine breaks disulfide bonds in mucoproteins, and guaifenesin increases mucus hydration to ease expulsion.</p>
</blockquote><p>You say: "Ambroxol reduces mucus viscosity "<br />
Chat says: "There are already several mucolytic agents available in the U.S. market. "</p>
<p>"Mucolytics...break up mucus in your lungs and make it easier to cough out. "</p>
<p>So, what you're saying is that "Ambroxol " is not a "mucolytic " agent, but some other kind of chemical.  OK, got it.  But GPT doesn't make that clear so it's not clear it knows the difference.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?commentID=160760074">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?commentID=160760074</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-left-on-fda-peer-approval">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-left-on-fda-peer-approval</a></p><p>Votes: 173⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?commentID=160760074</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-left-on-fda-peer-approval.html?commentID=160760074</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[blue jay]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 12:26:59 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>