<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 10:06:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The Prisoner’s Dilemma of Non-Competes by abitoftruth]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>If the companies were all reasonable (for example always paying for the time period that was covering the non compete) there would have been no action taken.</p>
<p>I got an internship through my college when I was 20 and had to sign a non-compete with the company. When I graduated there was a recession and the company had no positions available for me to apply to. </p>
<p>The next company (same industry, different products) required me to obtain a waiver from the first company. They at first refused to give me one and claimed it was FOREVER (this was before constraints from lawsuits). I went to my college explaining that their partner companies were preventing me from gaining employment with the degree they had bestowed in an entire industry my internship was for, FOREVER.</p>
<p>While the company did end up writing a release due to the pressure from the college (except for the type of products I worked on and with a 2 year time limit) it was ridiculous in the first place that my job prospects were literally put at risk, the significant time I had to spend and the stress of not knowing the outcome.</p>
<p>I for one am glad to see it die the death it deserves.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/04/the-prisoners-dilemma-of-non-competes.html?commentID=160748979">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/04/the-prisoners-dilemma-of-non-competes.html?commentID=160748979</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/04/the-prisoners-dilemma-of-non-competes.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-prisoners-dilemma-of-non-competes">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/04/the-prisoners-dilemma-of-non-competes.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-prisoners-dilemma-of-non-competes</a></p><p>Votes: 104⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/04/the-prisoners-dilemma-of-non-competes.html?commentID=160748979</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/04/the-prisoners-dilemma-of-non-competes.html?commentID=160748979</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[abitoftruth]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 11:43:12 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>