<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 10:10:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on How tenure should be granted, circa 2024 by WillPearson]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Tyler has sometimes remarked that people overrate how smart he is and underrate how much he knows. I guess I shouldn’t be surprised that he makes the same mistake here, and continually fails to appreciate the value of creativity and insight and wisdom over the mechanistic reproduction and juxtaposition AIs so excel in.</p>
<p>I finally put some of my own writing into the NotebookLM ‘make me a podcast talking about this’ tool, and it’s very impressive how realistic and fun to listen to the output it creates is. But it completely neuters and de-nuances what it takes to be the central points, and does so, unsurprisingly, squarely in the direction of the status quo. It turns everything into a reflection of what people *in general* say about x, y, or z. This is so antithetical to any pursuit of knowledge! How can this be what we want.</p>
<p>I used to recommend this blog to artist friends, saying : ‘This is an economist who listens to Lachenmann! What could be more recommending than that?’ But my assumption was that Tyler had some understanding of both, some appreciation…. not just that he’d scraped the data and can retrieve it and present it at potentially appropriate times. Don’t sell yourself short, Tyler!</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/how-tenure-should-be-granted-circa-2024.html?commentID=160817401">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/how-tenure-should-be-granted-circa-2024.html?commentID=160817401</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/how-tenure-should-be-granted-circa-2024.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-tenure-should-be-granted-circa-2024">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/how-tenure-should-be-granted-circa-2024.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=how-tenure-should-be-granted-circa-2024</a></p><p>Votes: 61⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/how-tenure-should-be-granted-circa-2024.html?commentID=160817401</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/how-tenure-should-be-granted-circa-2024.html?commentID=160817401</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[WillPearson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 11:03:17 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>