<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 22:07:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on That was then, this is now, NBA edition by Anthropologist]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to rayward:</p><blockquote><p>Charles Barkley isn't happy: cable (his employer is TNT) is losing NBA media rights to the big three, Disney (ESPN/ABC), NBC, and Amazon. Concentration of wealth in America. What could go wrong? America loves its entertainment, no entertainment more than sports. Ask me again why America isn't as innovative as in the past? Way down here the big story is sports, namely the state's flagship university. No, DeSantis didn't do it, again, media rights did: a lawsuit was filed Tuesday by a former high school star quarterback who in his lawsuit claims that in 2023 the University of Florida reneged on a $13.85 million plus guaranteed NIL (name, image, likeness) payoff if he signed with the University. What could go wrong? Media (that includes the internet) owns America, and by extension, Americans. </p>
<p>I read an article today that indicated the titans of Silicon Valley are signing on to the Trump campaign. I've commented many times that, like water seeking its own level, capital seeks the highest rate of return. And today, the highest rate of return for capital is Trump, who promises a large tax cut for capital, and specifically for the titans of Silicon Valley, Trump promises to back off antitrust enforcement against tech. This isn't a moral choice for capital: capital doesn't make moral choices, it's a law of nature. Like a teenage boy seeking what teenage boys seek whatever the cost: it's not morality, it's nature.</p>
</blockquote><p>Oddly, capitalism is actually a cultural system like any other. But it pretends that its brand of culture is a culture-free battle for the buffet, the devil take the hindmost. But not all cultures are on board. Just 50 years ago here, this run for the money would have seemed somewhat ugly. And the Trobriand Islanders played cricket, but the ideal game was a tie. It actually takes a lot of moral labor to create a society in which the market is eroticized more than other people, and in which people are commodified while society is operated for the benefit of commodities and their reproduction.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760627">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760627</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition</a></p><p>Votes: 223⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760627</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760627</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthropologist]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 18:50:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on That was then, this is now, NBA edition by Dinwar]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Edward Burke:</p><blockquote><p>In ancient times, sigh alas alack, at least gladiators fought to the death: entertainment value was held to be commensurate to the spectacle, someone could argue.</p>
<p>That our GDP is calibrated to such investments in ephemera constitutes a sign of woefully misplaced priorities, esp. in light in significant challenges we and our GDP face in the world today. (Remind me how much municipal and state "investment" commonly goes into the periodic construction of stadia and colosseum venues, which may not of itself be enormous, but then there's all that corruption that professional athletics has engendered, perhaps possibly maybe in post-secondary institutions of "higher learning" most of all.)</p>
</blockquote><p>As Anonymous said, most gladiators weren't killed. And it's notable that the circus--ie, chariot races--were more popular than the gladiators. Rome was built by its equivalent of NASCAR, not by its equivalent of MMA. </p>
<p>As for corruption, it depends on the definition. What Romans called normal business practice, we would call an insane amount of corruption. But in Rome it was expected. If you're my client OF COURSE I'm going to give you the lucrative stone contract to build my new Circus Minimus; that's what this relationship is about (you'll repay by having your family support me in the next election), and to not do so would be a direct insult. Giving the contract to a friend would paint me as an honorable man, someone worthy of authority; to not do so would cost me most of my status in the community. Nowadays it's considered scandalous if you even know the guy that owns the stone company; if you do, at minimum you have to disclose a potential conflict of interest and the bid review process is subject to an insane amount of oversight. My point being, before we talk about the novelty of corruption it would be wise to make sure we're comparing apples to apples.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760643">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760643</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition</a></p><p>Votes: 218⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760643</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760643</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dinwar]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 19:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on That was then, this is now, NBA edition by (Not That) Bill O'Reilly]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Andao:</p><blockquote><p>That doesn't make sense. People travel for work all the time and pay taxes according to where they live.</p>
</blockquote><p>Look up the term "jock tax." There are state/local tax laws designed not to implicate a business trip for some middle manager but to still extract their pound of flesh from unsympathetic out-of-town athletes.* I work in a professional services industry where we bill by the hour, and I have to code each of my time entries based on where I actually perform the work so we have a compliance audit trail. </p>
<p>*Hilariously, this can actually lead to situations where an athlete loses money by performing better. Forbes or WSJ or the like had an article a few years back about how Cam Newton's bonus for making the Super Bowl with Panthers was worth less than the tax liability that the state of California (where the game was played that year) would impose on his overall salary for spending a week there.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760725">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760725</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition</a></p><p>Votes: 154⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760725</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760725</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[(Not That) Bill O'Reilly]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 03:12:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on *GOAT* is now a free audiobook by Vulcidian]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>That picture of the goat with glasses is cringe incarnate. Have we hit peak AItman?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760512">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760512</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook</a></p><p>Votes: 188⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760512</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760512</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Vulcidian]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 13:22:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on *GOAT* is now a free audiobook by Edward Burke]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Vulcidian:</p><blockquote><p>That picture of the goat with glasses is cringe incarnate. Have we hit peak AItman?</p>
</blockquote><p>For some contemporaries it conjures (or can conjure) at least two associated associations:</p>
<p>1) it suggests the title and cover of The Rolling Stones' album Goats Head Soup; </p>
<p>and</p>
<p>2) with a suitable goatee of venerable length, it conjures images of The Devil (aka Lucifer, Satan), as in "Sympathy for . . .".</p>
<p>Great company for Tyler to keep for a change, get him away from his Beatles infatuations for a while.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760527">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760527</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook</a></p><p>Votes: 185⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760527</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760527</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Edward Burke]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 14:01:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on *GOAT* is now a free audiobook by blue jay]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Edward Burke:</p><blockquote><p>For some contemporaries it conjures (or can conjure) at least two associated associations:</p>
<p>1) it suggests the title and cover of The Rolling Stones' album Goats Head Soup; </p>
<p>and</p>
<p>2) with a suitable goatee of venerable length, it conjures images of The Devil (aka Lucifer, Satan), as in "Sympathy for . . .".</p>
<p>Great company for Tyler to keep for a change, get him away from his Beatles infatuations for a while.</p>
</blockquote><p>"get him away from his Beatles infatuations for a while."</p>
<p>The rolling stones are just a bar band.  But I dig all the different tunings Keith uses.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760557">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760557</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook</a></p><p>Votes: 184⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760557</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760557</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[blue jay]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 14:56:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on *GOAT* is now a free audiobook by Daniel Plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>My guess is that the voice is Wallace Michael Shawn aka The Toy Story Dinosaur.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760509">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760509</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook</a></p><p>Votes: 184⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760509</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760509</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Plant]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 13:13:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Don’t bother learning about this one, unless you already know what I am talking about by Susan D Einbinder]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As the current Chair of an IRB (and a member of one or another for 20 years), technically, review is only required if the study has a few sources of federal funding BUT our mandate is quite simple:  Protect participants.  This study exposes the names of people competing for jobs, which might - might - put one or more of them at risk at their current jobs or by disclosing information that would otherwise remain private.  This means the study has to be reviewed by the IRB.  Not sure it would fly, either ....</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760692">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760692</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about</a></p><p>Votes: 110⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760692</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760692</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Susan D Einbinder]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 22:25:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Don’t bother learning about this one, unless you already know what I am talking about by superdestroyer]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Ricardo:</p><blockquote><p>I will disregard the title because I wasn't aware of this particular case but I do know a few things about IRBs.</p>
<p>Based on current standards, I don't see the argument for not approving the experiment. Is there genuine uncertainty over whether having your paper tweeted out by a prominent account helps you on the job market? Maybe not, but the authors would have had to do their literature review and justify why this is a legitimate research question. If their arguments were flawed, someone should explain why.</p>
<p>Second, is a scarce resource involved in the experiment? You could dispute this but I think it is intuitive that attention on social media is a bit of a scarce resource. If a prominent Twitter account tweets out links to 500+ papers, the message gets diluted compared to if it only tweets out ~250. If there is a scarce resource that is probably being somewhat arbitrarily and unfairly distributed in the real-world and, given the research question above, that is most of what you need to pass IRB.</p>
<p>Informed consent is typically not demanded in real-world experiments like this where you are not surveying people or bringing them into a laboratory setting.</p>
<p>However, there is an entirely separate <b>professional ethics</b> at stake that is beyond the scope of what IRBs deal with. Should there be a code of conduct among economists that they should publicly promote academic work in an unbiased manner and should have no ulterior motives when they do so? If so, then this experiment would violate that code. If not, it just becomes a reputational thing. If people know that the next time you promote a certain paper it may be because you are running an RCT or doing something other than strictly promoting all of the high-quality work you are coming across, people may listen to your recommendations less.</p>
</blockquote><p>Social science research goes through IRB all of the time.  This type of research would probably fly through with expedited review due to minimal risk.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760504">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760504</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about</a></p><p>Votes: 159⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760504</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/dont-bother-learning-about-this-one-unless-you-already-know-what-i-am-talking-about.html?commentID=160760504</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[superdestroyer]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 12:48:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The death of the AI safety movement? by RAD]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As of May, 2024:<br />
p(DOOM) -&gt; zero<br />
QED</p>
<p>The core DOOMer assumption was that a misaligned Artificial Super Intelligence (ASI) would crush humanity like ants after a fast-takeoff FOOM event; the AI Singularity. </p>
<p>These Natural Language Machines are not AGI, never mind ASI, the take-off is slow, and the energy/compute infrastructure looks to be constrained by the pace and performance of human managed mega-projects. Always check your assumptions. </p>
<p>Having said that, these Natural Language Machines are powerful tools posed to unlock the vast amount of unstructured data previously opaque to software. The question is how deep the disruption will be. The range seems to be from a fourth pillar in the web/mobile/cloud revolution to a new AI-driven digital revolution that dwarfs the previous 30-year epoch.</p>
<p>Multi-step agents working on long time horizons seem to be on the cusp of becoming mainstream. Self-iterating LLM agents may accelerate the pace of innovation and adoption. May you live in interesting times.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760461">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760461</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement</a></p><p>Votes: 175⬆ 7⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760461</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760461</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[RAD]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 08:06:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The death of the AI safety movement? by M]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>TC: <i>"Lawmakers seem to understand that they would rather face the risks of US-based AI systems than have to contend with Chinese developments without a US counterweight. The early history of Covid, when the Chinese government behaved recklessly and nontransparently, has driven this realization home."</i></p>
<p>It's not necessarily the only reasoning though. If China is threatening to the US, it might be *more* important that the US not commit acts of self-harm, via "unsafe AI", that weaken it in the face of Chinese competition?</p>
<p>It's entirely possible that less "safe AI" by US -&gt; more fraud (including academic fraud that weakens the standing of Western science), more crime, more mental health disorders and more impenetrable and complex financial engineering in the US -&gt; US is relatively weakened to China.</p>
<p>TC perhaps thinks about the US's strength in the same way that US's frontier companies think about it; in terms of their product sophistication and their valuations and the total value of the publicly traded stock market and so on. But it's possible that these can increase up while their products weaken US society and its economy. The Magnificent Seven are not America. Startups are not America.</p>
<p>On balance I'm still optimistic about these technologies (they offer the prospect of release from the most repetitive and poorly paid parts of the service economy, and that's the least of it). But all possibilities should be considered. It's entirely possible that the tortoises beat the hare here.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760470">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760470</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement</a></p><p>Votes: 167⬆ 4⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760470</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760470</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[M]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 09:19:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The death of the AI safety movement? by JustAnotherScientist]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>AI safety?  Eh.  Lots of things aren't safe.  Danger is the spice of life.</p>
<p>AI Notkilleveryoneism?  That one I'm firmly behind.  With most things I don't worry about being replaced as the smartest species on the planet.  </p>
<p>AI is awesome, and I use it every day in my work.  It frees my marginal hour to work on more important things the AI can't help with... yet.  But I only slightly worry that the AI will eventually leave me with no margin to move to.  That would be a weird world, but I can deal with weird.</p>
<p>What worries me is that the simplest way to do a job better is to get more resources to do it.  Even without a foom, when we set the AI a goal of "make money", we see naturally in humans that this leads to a push to gather more power to further the goal.</p>
<p>That works OK for humans, and yes I'm OK with capitalism.  But I'm that future world, a human making decisions becomes a disadvantage.  The equilibrium looks like everyone puts more and more control in the AI's digital hands. </p>
<p>In that equilibrium the competitive race will be to put more and more computer and energy in your AI's control. US, China, OpenAI, whomever. </p>
<p>If humanity's capabilities are not a special ceiling level on the exponential scaling laws, and I see no reason to believe we are, we become a lot less relevant.  Personally, I like driving the future, but maybe a post scarcity abundant Utopia less thataway.  I am skeptical, but whatever. </p>
<p>But whether you call it foom, picture Skynet raining fire, imagine curious Yellow spreading -- the equilibrium looks like a technology with exponential scaling laws stuck on a loop of runaway growth locked in by lack of coordination... even if (when) most humans don't want that.</p>
<p>And ultimately, that system has a poorly understood objective function while we increasingly arrive to give it agency to take it's own actions and set it's own sub goals. </p>
<p>What do we do if a system like that decides our atoms could be used better for something else?</p>
<p>I don't think this movement has peaked.  I do think it has grown quite rapidly, but I think it will continue to grow each time something sufficiently unexpected jolts the zeitgeist beyond the usual boiling frog background tempo.  Compute limits driving reporting at the frontier level are a light touch and an elegant solution; 10^26 is a generous runway.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760508">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760508</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement</a></p><p>Votes: 158⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760508</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760508</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[JustAnotherScientist]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 13:10:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The death of the AI safety movement? by MC]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Comments of this post that were critical were deleted. I can't say for sure it was by TC but they made some points I think should be here so I will try to reiterate them (probably poorly). </p>
<p>TC's bias on this subject is pretty clear. He is cherry picking examples and nowhere is there mention of incidents on MR of Jan Leike's resignation. (he just gestures broadly to everything and calls it 'safetyism').</p>
<p>TC doesn't mention or elaborate on the actual arguments of 'doomers'. He just disparagingly calls them 'worriers' and is using his site to declare preemptive victory in order to hurt morale and generally gaslight people who are concerned about this technology.</p>
<p>The fact that TC is this biased on this subject, having for years seemed to be level headed and fair-minded casts doubts on his past musings.</p>
<p>The fact that the earliest critical comments (that had the most upvotes btw) on this post are nowhere to be seen only strengthen the points laid out in them imo.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760660">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760660</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement</a></p><p>Votes: 136⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760660</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/the-death-of-the-ai-safety-movement.html?commentID=160760660</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[MC]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 20:26:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>