<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 10:09:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Facts about Britain by Abby P]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>A lot of this can be traced backed to the Planning Act of 1947 which gave NIMBYs and homeowners effective veto rights on new housing and infrastructure. Over time, they've used is effectively to strangle building anything.</p>
<p>Concepts like Conservation Areas in cities and Areas Of Natural Beauty have been fantastic levers for these people.</p>
<p>The popular show Clarkson's Farm shows the mind-numbing stupidity of these rules. He runs a farm in the Cotswolds and wants to covert a small lambing shed to a restaurant. The planning process he goes through is emblematic of the stagnation. His first application has support from most local people but is rejected on the basis of a few people who live miles and miles away, mostly from one local who has money to hire a lawyer to stop it and from the Council for the Preservation of Rural England complaining about lights from it spoiling the dark sky at 10pm. This restaurant is in a farm in the middle of fields. Appealing the decision would cost £250,000. </p>
<p>He is also forced to change the green roof of his farm shop to a grey slate because it's in an AONB and every building must be similar. Planning rules are useful to make it expensive to build anything.</p>
<p>He wanted to convert a dilapidated barn to a restaurant but needs council permission to build a farm track on his farm to get people there. They said no.</p>
<p>In "Conservation" areas of my town (a suburb of London), we can't change colour of front doors without council permission. Locals - mostly greedy homeowners who don't want more housing competition - complained because 4 new flats "could be seen from High Street and are therefore detrimental to the character of the area".  The local pensioner society has plenty to time to go to planning meetings to object, and they do this a lot; and I pay for their triple-locked-pension-benefits, free public transport passes, and assorted benefits while they strangle housing. The council’s mantra is “Putting residents first”, which translates to “putting homeowners finances first”.</p>
<p>The council wants to designate more streets on my area as conservation zones - a convenient tool for NIMBYs to use to stop anything.</p>
<p>A big example - plans to build an Oxford-Cambridge transport corridor between 2 areas with tech and startup activity. And we have this https://stopthearc.org/, who primary goal is to "challenge the concept of the Arc as an economic entity or as a basis for planning". While they may not succeed, they will delay the process for years and escalate costs. Many developers give up. Many don’t even bother to propose new ideas because it will be costly with low chance of approvals.</p>
<p>We can go on and on with small and big examples like this.</p>
<p>The Conservative and Liberal Democrat parties have explicitly pro NIMBY policies, and they campaign on this. The Greens are beginning to go in that direction, “we want wind power, but those electric lines need to be buried at 10x cost because local NIMBYs protest.”</p>
<p>Greedy homeowners have used the Planning Act for decades to prop up values for their 20:1 leveraged bets on their homes. The Brits think property, property, property as their pension pot; not investment in real companies that make to do real things. They will go to extremes to protest even the slightest increase in housing supply.</p>
<p>The British stagnation is self-inflicted, and it all goes back to the Planning Act of 1947.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/facts-about-britain.html?commentID=160814377">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/facts-about-britain.html?commentID=160814377</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/facts-about-britain.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=facts-about-britain">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/facts-about-britain.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=facts-about-britain</a></p><p>Votes: 81⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/facts-about-britain.html?commentID=160814377</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/facts-about-britain.html?commentID=160814377</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Abby P]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 07:01:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Facts about Britain by Crusader]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>If the US had any compassion, we’d send a mission of 50 of our top regulators to the UK to help them pass more regulation and fix this mess.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/facts-about-britain.html?commentID=160814349">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/facts-about-britain.html?commentID=160814349</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/facts-about-britain.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=facts-about-britain">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/facts-about-britain.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=facts-about-britain</a></p><p>Votes: 57⬆ 5⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/facts-about-britain.html?commentID=160814349</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/facts-about-britain.html?commentID=160814349</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Crusader]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 04:59:26 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>