<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 10:09:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Claims about Ireland (from the comments) by EBC]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm Irish, was reared there, studied there for University, worked there for a couple of years but have spent around 8 years abroad. Some of this comment is true and some is inaccurate. </p>
<p>The revolutionaries who were successful in 1921 were mostly not social liberals and the creed of the state was very conservative- they've been called, with a reasonable justification, the most conservative revolutionaries of all time! </p>
<p>There is an unwillingness by Irish people to address how the biggest problem in Irish society, i.e. housing, is mostly due to government overregulation, but much of this is done at an EU level. You do hear facile/ridiculous comments from many younger Irish people frequently to the tune of "I wouldn't mind paying more taxes so long as I received better services/it was spend looking after the vulnerable" which ignores that there is already a large surplus, spending has skyrocketed since 2019 with a fairly negligible improvement in public services, most money will just go on special interest groups like public sector unions who will swallow the cash without offering any improvements in productivity etc. These people will complain about any and all attempts to cut taxes, deregulate etc but will complain incessantly about their inability to grow their wealth, get on the housing ladder etc. </p>
<p>But there is also a different block of younger people with a very different mindset, who very quick to jump to lower tax jurisdictions like Dubai (using exit rather than voice as it were). This emigration is a very positive thing for the people who do it- I'm always amazed more young British people, continental Europeans etc are not just quicker to leave their countries and start afresh, even for a limited period. </p>
<p>I also dispute that the class system is oppressive in Ireland. While housing bleeds into everything, University attendances are high, reaching good jobs in the traditional professions/industry/politics is much more accessible than in other countries; it's creeping in a bit, but so far, Ireland has avoided the poisonous credentialism and networking that is necessary in so many other countries to get ahead. An ambitious and hard-working young person who didn't study at an elite university, doesn't have family money can still find themselves with good options for upward social mobility in their chosen profession.</p>
<p>I agree on the points about the inadequacy of public transport. I also agree that public healthcare is poor but the fact that 50% of the population can access private healthcare shows it is not particularly exclusionary- it generally costs €2500-3000 p.a with a minimal excess. It won't cover everything but it's adequate and most people who have it are satisfied. I also agree that the legal system is shambolically slow and ineffectual but would add that while it's not discussed much, Irish judges are generally of low quality and quite activist in their rulings.  I'm not sure are they much worse than in the UK, the USA however. The observation that the civil service are an incompetent racket is also true. This applies to other public sector agencies, quangos as well. I'd add there also exists an NGO-industrial complex- despite, the "N" and the "G", most of their funding comes from the government. They then use that money to lobby the government for more money, as well as lobbying for socially destructive and unpopular policies, often quite successfully. </p>
<p>There is appalling inter-generational solidarity, with older pensioners having no interest in helping the young but instead being more concerned with voting themselves more government entitlements. Again though, I'm not sure how uniquely Irish this is, the same seems to be happening in the UK. If anything, it's less galling in Ireland as at least the older generation had to live in an impoverished backwater until ~1990 and were around to build the country into something that for all its faults, is better than what came before. Whereas in the UK/US/continental Europe, the beneficiaries of government largesse today seem to have contributed little to improving the country and in fact have often gone to great lengths to make it worse.</p>
<p>In terms of what Ireland does well, the IDA is good at attracting foreign direct investment which has greatly aided our complete economic transformation since 1990. While performance in rankings vary, most Irish people are happy with the quality of the education they received, from primary to tertiary level.<br />
Political polarisation is low in elected representatives, the media and the electorate at large. This may change, as the vast majority of the public are very angry with the abuse of the asylum system and its use as a backdoor for economic migration that would otherwise not be allowed. But for now, I think polarisation remains low. If Ireland continues to allow irregular migration numbers to increase, social cohesion will fracture, as it has across the rest of Europe where governments have been unresponsive to the wishes of the majority of the electorates to reduce this irregular migration and its associated enormous social costs.</p>
<p>Leaving that big issue to one side though, Irish elected politicians, while often criticised are generally sane and normal and try to develop and execute policies rather than spending their days fighting culture wars on social media. For instance, housing supply was again recognised as a massive problem around the mid-2010s. While it probably took the change of government in 2020 for meaningful measures to be taken, the fact is that through a variety of schemes, housing starts and completions have increased considerably in recent years i.e. there has at least been an attempt and some success in dealing with this issue and actually attempting to govern.</p>
<p>So I think while this post makes some good points, I think it paints an overly-negative picture of the country.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/claims-about-ireland-from-the-comments.html?commentID=160807823">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/claims-about-ireland-from-the-comments.html?commentID=160807823</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/claims-about-ireland-from-the-comments.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=claims-about-ireland-from-the-comments">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/claims-about-ireland-from-the-comments.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=claims-about-ireland-from-the-comments</a></p><p>Votes: 62⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/claims-about-ireland-from-the-comments.html?commentID=160807823</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/claims-about-ireland-from-the-comments.html?commentID=160807823</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[EBC]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 09:53:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Does the current structure of capital gains taxes provide interest-free loans? by Mark T]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Mathews’ argument is idiotic. It assumes his desired result as the correct outcome, then defines the status quo as the error. Intellectual garbage. </p>
<p>It’s like, you know, if we criminalized speech, you’d be in jail now.  Ergo, your freedom of speech is a privilege afforded by the government, for which you may be justly charged a fee.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/does-the-current-structure-of-capital-gains-taxes-provide-interest-free-loans.html?commentID=160807584">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/does-the-current-structure-of-capital-gains-taxes-provide-interest-free-loans.html?commentID=160807584</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/does-the-current-structure-of-capital-gains-taxes-provide-interest-free-loans.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=does-the-current-structure-of-capital-gains-taxes-provide-interest-free-loans">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/does-the-current-structure-of-capital-gains-taxes-provide-interest-free-loans.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=does-the-current-structure-of-capital-gains-taxes-provide-interest-free-loans</a></p><p>Votes: 43⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/does-the-current-structure-of-capital-gains-taxes-provide-interest-free-loans.html?commentID=160807584</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/does-the-current-structure-of-capital-gains-taxes-provide-interest-free-loans.html?commentID=160807584</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark T]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 19:49:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Ireland fact of the day by dearieme]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>"the poverty line, defined as 60 per cent of the median disposable household income."</p>
<p>If people insist on calling inequality "poverty" so be it.  But in that case what should we call genuine poverty?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/ireland-fact-of-the-day-6.html?commentID=160807360">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/ireland-fact-of-the-day-6.html?commentID=160807360</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/ireland-fact-of-the-day-6.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=ireland-fact-of-the-day-6">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/ireland-fact-of-the-day-6.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=ireland-fact-of-the-day-6</a></p><p>Votes: 55⬆ 5⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/ireland-fact-of-the-day-6.html?commentID=160807360</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/ireland-fact-of-the-day-6.html?commentID=160807360</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[dearieme]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 13:34:26 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>