<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 10:07:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on 13.9 percent less democracy? by Mikk]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I have to clarify a bit.<br />
In 1940, Estonia was annexed and occupied by the Soviet Union. Most states, including the United States, did not recognize this annexation. De jure, the Estonian Republic continued to exist even though, de facto, it was occupied by the Soviets. When Estonia regained its independence in 1991, it was not considered a new state but rather a continuation of the pre-1940 state. This had many legal consequences. For instance, the Estonian Republic reclaimed its pre-1940 embassy buildings. The United Kingdom returned the gold that the Estonian Republic had deposited in the Bank of England before 1940. People who owned property before 1940 but lost it during the Soviet occupation got their property back, and so on.</p>
<p>One of these legal consequences was that people (mostly Russian speakers) who had arrived during the Soviet occupation did not automatically receive Estonian citizenship. However, citizenship is not denied to them. To obtain Estonian citizenship, there is a residency requirement of 2 or 5 years, and applicants must pass an Estonian language exam. Most Russian speakers have applied for and obtained Estonian citizenship. Those who have not,  6.9% and 7% of the population, have chosen not to do so. Estonian citizenship is not denied to them; they have the right to obtain it but prefer not to.</p>
<p>For instance, stateless persons, while it may sound problematic, have permanent residency in Estonia, which comes with some benefits: they have visa-free access to the European Union and, until recently, also to Russia (Estonian citizens do not have visa-free access to Russia). They have the right to participate in Estonian local elections. As non-citizens, they are not drafted into the Estonian military (Estonia, like Israel and Finland, has mandatory military service). The only right they do not have as non-citizens is the ability to participate in national elections. And guess what? Many people do not care about voting in elections.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/13-9-percent-less-democracy.html?commentID=160772927">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/13-9-percent-less-democracy.html?commentID=160772927</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/13-9-percent-less-democracy.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=13-9-percent-less-democracy">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/13-9-percent-less-democracy.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=13-9-percent-less-democracy</a></p><p>Votes: 74⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/13-9-percent-less-democracy.html?commentID=160772927</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/13-9-percent-less-democracy.html?commentID=160772927</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mikk]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 07:17:04 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>