<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 10:03:59 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Henry Oliver’s *Second Act* is coming out in the UK by Etalon d'Silomar]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Gardel:</p><blockquote><p>Hopefully there are some great stories of 70-somethings who have achieved success after sitting around watching Fox News for a decade!</p>
</blockquote><p>I think at least one of us may become lead grouse at his local McDonald's.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?commentID=160756043">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?commentID=160756043</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk</a></p><p>Votes: 235⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?commentID=160756043</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?commentID=160756043</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Etalon d'Silomar]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 13:47:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Henry Oliver’s *Second Act* is coming out in the UK by Gardel]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to ndp_jwh:</p><blockquote><p>Hey fellow MR commenters! There's hope for us yet!</p>
</blockquote><p>Hopefully there are some great stories of 70-somethings who have achieved success after sitting around watching Fox News for a decade!</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?commentID=160756025">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?commentID=160756025</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk</a></p><p>Votes: 235⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?commentID=160756025</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?commentID=160756025</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Gardel]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 12:37:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Henry Oliver’s *Second Act* is coming out in the UK by rayward]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to rayward:</p><blockquote><p>Sailer raises the point I would make (the fluid intelligence that rises with age) but he doesn't give credit to age that it deserves. We used to associate age with wisdom, and sought the advice and counsel of seniors but not so much anymore. What is "knowledge"? Is it mainly the information, the data, that is stored in our brains? Is it the ability to use that data analytically for better decision-making? Or is it merely about access to data: the ability to mine vast quantities of data stored on a hard drive? If it's the latter, then what's a human good for? The human brain will shrink as the A.I.'s brain expands. In science fiction of the past, humans were depicted as having large heads and shrunken bodies, the former from use and the latter from non-use. Today's science fiction would depict the opposite: large, well-developed bodies (all that leisure time while A.I. does the "work") and a shrunken head (the human brain has less to do).</p>
<p>An aside, loss of respect for seniors has two sources. One, the absence of a well-developed access ability: seniors don't even know how to use computers to access all the data available. Two, advancements in medicine and nutrition: seniors are living longer and (call them) "super seniors" have less cognition. In my profession, law, "senior partners" were highly valued for their "knowledge". Not so much any more: they've been sent out to pasture to make room for the young, smart lawyers who know how to use not only computers but A.I. Here's one noticeable difference: "senior partners" require their assistants to print a hard copy for them to read (contracts, pleadings, letters, research product, etc.) while youthful lawyers don't print anything: they read everything on the monitor. I'm old but I adopted the habit of using my computers to create, read, and store all the data in my practice, while few lawyers my age ever did. To emphasize the point, if I email (a digital copy of) a document to a "senior partner", it likely will disappear in the bowels of his hard drive once his assistant prints a hard copy. "Senior partners" still rely on file cabinets not computer files. And their assistants adopt the same filing method: they never learn to create files and sub-files and sub-sub files because the "senior partners" wouldn't access them, and wouldn't know how. This overly long paragraph makes the point about how seniors don't have the same respect as they once did because they lack the skills to "access the data". And this isn't something will will disappear with the current generation, as the data and the access to the data continue to evolve and with it the skills to access and use it effectively. "Senior partners" will get younger and younger until "don't trust anyone over age 30" becomes reality. Good luck with that.</p>
<p>Not that any of this matters. I learned last night that there is a large collection of meteors traveling through space leaving a path of destruction in its wake, and that it passes earth every 12,000 years. That's a relief. No it's not: the last time it passed the earth was 11,970 years ago. Have a nice day.</p>
</blockquote><p>Scratch the last paragraph. Last night I fell asleep watching a podcast on my i-pad, and woke up to loud voices several hours later from a podcast six years ago. I won't mention the participants, but I didn't realize I had awaken to a podcast recorded six years ago, as I listened to impending doom from an asteroid. Anyway, that is an old issue that, like many, came and went, I suppose like podcasts generally. Anyway, it was a podcast by a host I never listen to (although his guests are favorites of mine), and why it came on my i-pad while I was asleep is a mystery. Maybe my dog did it. Anyway, we still have 24 years to go, but even with six years cut from doomsday, I won't be around for the show.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?commentID=160756009">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?commentID=160756009</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk</a></p><p>Votes: 228⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?commentID=160756009</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/henry-olivers-second-act-is-coming-out-in-the-uk.html?commentID=160756009</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[rayward]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 11:37:23 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>