<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 10:09:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on My excellent Conversation with Philip Ball by PM]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It seems like this might actually be meant ironically or as a kind of quiet critique:</p>
<p>"and I think three of them, so far, have shown they are able to answer any question I might plausibly throw their way. Philip, I believe, is number four."</p>
<p>Only 3 people so far have been so clueless and apparently unable to qualify their own credibility and the bounds of their value that they willingly jump on any question Tyler asks.</p>
<p>In a sense o think that characterizes the conversation. Ball illustrates the silly and common view that Science is an attribute of a person or a group - like a Religion or Party - instead of a way of describing a set of methods for answering questions or a capability that can be applied and mis-applied (like logic).</p>
<p>Clearly he knows and has expertise in specific areas of science and scientific publishing. But then in question after question his answers fall back on some personal opinion that reflects a social value or political sensibility rather than anything remotely similar to a scientific way of unbundling a question and discriminating between forms and levels of evidence.</p>
<p>It's like he thinks he knows Science and therefore any answer he gives is Scientific.</p>
<p>Why would "we" (as I'd there is such a thing) need artificial wombs? </p>
<p>Uhhh, "I dunno" - he doesn't see any reason why it's needed and therefore it isn't. And it isn't possible now, so "it's probably not possible".</p>
<p>Bizarre. </p>
<p>I found this one of the most unimpressive and weirdly (perhaps enlighteningly?) low quality conversations ive heard in a while.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball.html?commentID=160808224">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball.html?commentID=160808224</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball</a></p><p>Votes: 66⬆ 9⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball.html?commentID=160808224</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/my-excellent-conversation-with-philip-ball.html?commentID=160808224</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[PM]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 05:49:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on More on taxing unrealized capital gains (from my email) by Naveen K]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In the original post, Tyler seemed to be baffled by the motivations of those who propose this. Especially the "When so many promising developments in biotech and green energy seem to be on the way?  Why should we want to crush venture capital like this?". Tyler is overthinking this. The contradictions don't make sense because the purpose isn't revenue or taxing unrealized gains. </p>
<p>The simplest explanation is that many on the Left want to punish SV and VC because they visibly and vocally shifted to the Republicans this cycle in a way that left them shocked and embarrassed. The taking of wealth in the form of taxing unrealized gains is nothing more than a way of punishing their detractors. They thought they owned SV. No need to overthink further than that. </p>
<p>Look at the 2021 IRS tax data leak controversy and see how Democrats reacted to the IRS leak. Pretty much zero condemnation of the IRS leak which was a shocking breach of norms. Tyler <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2021/06/the-irs-tax-data-leak.html" rel="ugc">wrote there</a> "How many of them, in other contexts, will defend strong rights of privacy?  I guess that right is for everyone except rich people who create a lot of jobs and output".</p>
<p>It's the same anger you saw from the Left in 2017 at SV (Cambridge Analytica freakout) for letting Brexit and Trump happen as if Zuckerberg created populism. They they spent the next few years plotting revenge at SV. Taxing unrealized gains is also just plain revenge right now. Just look at how they treat Elon. </p>
<p>Keith Ellison, the former deputy chair of the Democratic National Committee yesterday was praising Brazil for suppressing Elon's Twitter. Just look at how long the WH held out before agreeing to take SpaceX's help despite astronauts' lives being on the line because they didn't want to give Elon/SpaceX a win. Biden held an EV summit in 2021 and refused to invite Elon to it.</p>
<p>It's both the stated and unstated policy of the Democratic party that you can leak the tax returns of the rich, cheat them out of their assets by forcing them to liquidate them, suppress their social media platforms if they don't bow down to the misinformation-disinformation-hate speech censorship regime etc.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/more-on-taxing-unrealized-capital-gains-from-my-email.html?commentID=160807933">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/more-on-taxing-unrealized-capital-gains-from-my-email.html?commentID=160807933</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/more-on-taxing-unrealized-capital-gains-from-my-email.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=more-on-taxing-unrealized-capital-gains-from-my-email">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/more-on-taxing-unrealized-capital-gains-from-my-email.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=more-on-taxing-unrealized-capital-gains-from-my-email</a></p><p>Votes: 61⬆ 19⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/more-on-taxing-unrealized-capital-gains-from-my-email.html?commentID=160807933</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/more-on-taxing-unrealized-capital-gains-from-my-email.html?commentID=160807933</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Naveen K]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 15:29:49 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>