<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 22:08:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on My Conversation with Musa al-Gharbi by Ricardo]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I didn't see the demand side being mentioned.</p>
<p>An important thing that happened to media in the 2010s and that, I think, has little historical precedent is the rise of tailored ads which, in turn, leads to a business model based on clicks.</p>
<p>The one thing that is now obvious about human nature is that people are attracted to conflict. An article with a headline of the form, "Person X denounced for racists comments" or "Controversy over Person Y's speech" will get lots of clicks. And the nature of social media also changes the way people interact with articles and video clips like this. In the 90s or before, people might have eventually gotten tired of outrage-based reporting. Today, though, even if you are tired of it, everyone on your social media feed and all of the podcast hosts and commentators you follow are not. If enough people start discussing some "controversy," you will be almost compelled to click on the clickbait and then get tailored ads served to you.</p>
<p>Look at CNN's website as a prime example. It does not strike me at all as the sort of thing "elites" would want to create if they were left to their own devices. It is exactly the sort of thing business people who were being measured based on click-related KPIs would create. There is usually "woke" stuff on their page but there is also just a lot of fluff in general compared to serious news. The common denominator here seems to obviously be what gets people to click and stay engaged.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/my-conversation-with-musa-al-gharbi.html?commentID=160823591">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/my-conversation-with-musa-al-gharbi.html?commentID=160823591</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/my-conversation-with-musa-al-gharbi.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=my-conversation-with-musa-al-gharbi">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/my-conversation-with-musa-al-gharbi.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=my-conversation-with-musa-al-gharbi</a></p><p>Votes: 46⬆ 4⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/my-conversation-with-musa-al-gharbi.html?commentID=160823591</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/my-conversation-with-musa-al-gharbi.html?commentID=160823591</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ricardo]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 08:09:38 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>