<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 22:08:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Jim Crow and Black Economic Progress After Slavery by Brandon Berg]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I took a look at this when it was doing the rounds in draft form a while back. This is being sold on social media as proof that the effects of slavery persist across several generations, but it doesn't really show that. In 1940 and 2023, the effects are mediated by location. The 1940 finding is obvious: of course Jim Crow policies suppressed black earnings when they were in force. The 2023 findings are explained by the fact that the South is poor in general; white Southerners earn less than whites in other parts of the country, too. </p>
<p>The reality is that we just don't have much evidence that poverty arising from purely exogenous causes persists across more than a generation or so. Chetty finds that rank-rank intergenerational elasticity of permanent income is only around 0.4, and much of that is surely due to heredity. This means that exogenous effects should be almost entirely washed out within two generations of elimination of the cause.</p>
<p>Low black SES is either endogenous, or it's due to severe discrimination continuing to this day. The idea that it's due to lingering effects from slavery or even Jim Crow is very difficult to reconcile with everything we know about intergenerational transmission of SES.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/jim-crow-and-black-economic-progress-after-slavery.html?commentID=160803687">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/jim-crow-and-black-economic-progress-after-slavery.html?commentID=160803687</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/jim-crow-and-black-economic-progress-after-slavery.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=jim-crow-and-black-economic-progress-after-slavery">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/jim-crow-and-black-economic-progress-after-slavery.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=jim-crow-and-black-economic-progress-after-slavery</a></p><p>Votes: 62⬆ 20⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/jim-crow-and-black-economic-progress-after-slavery.html?commentID=160803687</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/jim-crow-and-black-economic-progress-after-slavery.html?commentID=160803687</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Brandon Berg]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 07:37:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Why do the servers always want to take our cutlery and plates and glasses away? by extramsg]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As a restaurant consultant and restaurateur who spent a lot of time managing restaurants, I don't think the primary purpose is turning tables.  It's helpful in that regard.  But pre-bussing (taking plates and silver after a course is finished) is primarily about working efficiently.</p>
<p>Different styles of restaurants and different cultures have different norms, but I assume we're talking about a midscale restaurant, not a 2 or 3 star Michelin restaurant.  Typically those elite restaurants will use a brigade system and the tradition is to clear all plates only once all diners at a table have finished.  Charlie Trotter's (RIP) had the best service I've ever experienced in the US and they would have someone for each diner clear the plates and silver between each course, something more common in European fine dining.  They would wait until each person was clearly done with their course before doing so.  In a place like that, you pay for such service.  I think The French Laundry is currently $350 per person before drinks and tip.</p>
<p>At midscale restaurants, you typically have just one server per table.   There may be a busser, food runner, someone pouring water, etc, but that's becoming less common as labor becomes more expensive.  (Though it's more common in states with tip credit laws.)  Typically in such places a server will have about 6 tables.  That gives them just 10 minutes per table per hour, including taking orders, running food, running drinks, bussing tables, closing out checks, dealing with any issues with the bar or the kitchen, etc.</p>
<p>Pre-bussing allows a server to break up their duties into smaller units of work.  If you don't pre-bus, then when the table leaves you have a mountain of work to finish to clean the table.  You can cut that work in half or more by pre-bussing.  If you're spending all the time bussing that table (and there may be a couple tables that leave at the same time or sequentially), then that is more time that other customers have to wait to get their check, pay their check, get their order taken, get their drinks, etc, etc.</p>
<p>I would occasionally suggest a server pre-bus a table to encourage lingering customers to move along when we had other customers waiting for a table, but the main thing I trained servers to do was to pre-bus whenever the opportunity arose.  What you don't want a server doing is wasting time.  You want them to maximize productivity and customer service.  If they drop a check at one table, they should be pre-bussing another if possible as they return to the kitchen.  And most customers appreciate their table being cleared.  Customers will often stack dishes and push them to the side of the table if a server waits too long to pre-bus.  (And when customers do this, they often do it haphazardly which makes pre-bussing take more time and more likely that plates will get dropped or that silverware will get thrown in the trash.)</p>
<p>Typically neither the restaurant nor the server wants to make you feel rushed.  That means you're less likely to return and less likely to tip good.  If you had said that you feel like they pre-bus too quickly 20% instead of 80% of the time, I would just chalk it up to over-eager servers or the decline in server quality post-pandemic.  However, I think it's worth asking yourself if maybe your self- assessment as someone who doesn't linger might not be true relative to the average diner.  That 80% of the time you feel like they're grabbing your plate and silver too early suggests to me that you may just have an abnormal expectation for when your plate and silver should be taken.  Or maybe you send signals without realizing it that typically indicate a customer is finished, such as placing your napkin on your plate or placing your silverware on your plate or pushing your plate forward or reading Twitter and MR comments on your phone or watching 30 minutes of a movie or something like that.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?commentID=160803663">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?commentID=160803663</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away</a></p><p>Votes: 42⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?commentID=160803663</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?commentID=160803663</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[extramsg]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 06:14:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Why do the servers always want to take our cutlery and plates and glasses away? by Jordan]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I was a server for years in a few different restaurants. Clearing is trained by managers. </p>
<p>In my view it has multiple reasons that it has stayed a ritual in training. </p>
<p>1. Managers prefer quicker turnover as you said.<br />
2. On busy nights the dish pit is as important to keeping the flow as anyone and feeding the dish pit is part of the servers job in the ecosystem.<br />
3. Servers like getting more alcohol for a table and/or free refills in some establishments are a top priority of training. So "touching the table multiple times per evening is mandatory and we are told in training that if you leave with nothing you're not doing your job correctly.<br />
4. Learned behavior that guests get annoyed if plates are left too long and bad servers overcorrect.<br />
5. Like any good employee on a job, a good server learns the rules and then adjust them to the context (slow day vs full house or short staff back of house vs well oiled machine back of house) Bad servers are like mediocre employees, automatons when it comes to rules or overachievers who are blind to context. </p>
<p>These are the reasons and variations I've seen aside from one offs like servers mimicking how they like to be treated when they go out or bad multitasking skills and get overwhelmed with only 3 tables. </p>
<p>The best restaurants have server assistants. They perch up and watch guests more closely and clear at more appropriate times plus they do the free refills leaving the server open to work on charm/sales and drinks drinks drinks. Adding one tiny role to the restaurant ecosystem like an SA can make a world of difference for the customer dining experience.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?commentID=160803649">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?commentID=160803649</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away</a></p><p>Votes: 86⬆ 15⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?commentID=160803649</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?commentID=160803649</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 05:20:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Why do the servers always want to take our cutlery and plates and glasses away? by Niclas Berggren]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In Swedish restaurants, those things are not cleared from the table until everyone at the table has finished eating and put their cutlery down. It’s considered rude to take away plates, glasses and cutlery before all in the party are done, supposedly because it puts stress on those who eat at a slower pace.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?commentID=160803645">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?commentID=160803645</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away</a></p><p>Votes: 47⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?commentID=160803645</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/why-do-the-servers-always-want-to-take-our-cutlery-and-plates-and-glasses-away.html?commentID=160803645</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Niclas Berggren]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 05:11:12 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>