<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 10:07:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Has Argentina given up on dollarization? by M]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://time.com/6980600/javier-milei-argentina-interview/" rel="nofollow ugc">Time</a> on Milei's legislation so far (since there are usually questions about that on Argentina related posts on here):</p>
<p>"<i>Milei’s first 100 days came and went without any legislative achievements. An omnibus bill that would have given him sweeping executive powers and included measures ranging from the privatization of state entities to penalties for protesters stalled in committee. “If they expected that the President would change the way he is, that’s never going to happen,” Manuel Adorni, his exhausted-looking spokesman, told me in his small office in the Casa Rosada, sipping maté. Earlier in the day, Adorni had spent his press briefing shooting down questions from reporters about his boss’s mental health, spurred by Milei’s repeated reference to having five dogs, even though one is known to have died years ago. (“If the President says there are five dogs, there are five dogs, and that’s the end of it.”)</i>"</p>
<p>(The global zenith of forgetful leaders?)</p>
<p>Not yet anyway.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?commentID=160760827">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?commentID=160760827</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization</a></p><p>Votes: 128⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?commentID=160760827</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?commentID=160760827</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[M]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 13:16:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Has Argentina given up on dollarization? by M]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Some points on how Milei is going so far:</p>
<p><i><a href="https://www.economicsobservatory.com/what-economic-challenges-does-argentina-face-today" rel="nofollow ugc">Economics Observatory - Argentina under a new government: what are the big economic challenges?</a> (8th May 2024)</i></p>
<p>The context: "<i>Over the last decade, the country has witnessed a 10.4% drop in per capita income, and its history of sovereign defaults and restructurings has led to prohibitively high interest rates in international credit markets.</i>"</p>
<p>The source of the Milei fiscal surplus: "<i>Spending cuts have been deep and across the board, slashing real primary expenditures by 35% compared with last year.</p>
<p>On the one hand, non-discretionary spending is being adjusted below the inflation rate. For example, pensions decreased by 36% year-over-year and contributed the <b>lion’s share</b> of the overall fiscal adjustment, amounting to 43% of the total. On the other hand, the cuts include a significant nominal reduction in discretionary spending. <b>Capital spending</b> and transfers to provinces contributed 32% of the overall fiscal adjustment. Economic subsidies, particularly for energy firms, have been reduced at the expense of <b>accumulating arrears with utility companies</b>."</i></p>
<p>Mainly cutting pensions and capital expenditures on infrastructure. Still I guess you're only losing 16% of the vote base immediately (over 65s), and the airports won't fall down immediately.<br />
(Hence E. Barandiaran's comment on Milei largely giving up, electorally I guess, on the old in favour of leaning into the young).<br />
Relatively little day-to-day real terms cuts on public sector wages per worker, so far, by the looks of it.<br />
Falls in Economic Activity: "<i>Economic activity fell by <b>3.3% year-over-year per month in December, January and February</b>. Private estimates also suggest a <b>decline in March</b>.</i><i>"<br />
Separately an estimate for how much economic activity has fallen Year-on-Year in March (via a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/may/23/javier-milei-buenos-aires-argentina" rel="nofollow ugc">Guardian</a> article otherwise focused on Milei's rock frontman antics): "</i><i>Hours before Milei picked up the mic, the government’s statistics bureau announced that economic activity had fallen by a <b>whopping 8.4% in March</b> compared with the previous year."</i><br />
...</p>
<p>The Milei recession will be truly deep, deep, deep (perhaps Argentina will be &lt;20% down on per capita income from 15 years ago?), and it will fall predominantly on pensioners and infrastructure. But is there actually another alternative, or is chickens coming to roost?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?commentID=160760791">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?commentID=160760791</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization</a></p><p>Votes: 147⬆ 1⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?commentID=160760791</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?commentID=160760791</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[M]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 10:37:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Has Argentina given up on dollarization? by rayward]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The problem with the role of Sheriff Bart is that he is graded based on a scale with his start date as zero. If conditions deteriorate, the new sheriff is blamed not his predecessors.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?commentID=160760785">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?commentID=160760785</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization</a></p><p>Votes: 152⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?commentID=160760785</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/has-argentina-given-up-on-dollarization.html?commentID=160760785</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[rayward]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 10:02:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on That was then, this is now, NBA edition by Anthropologist]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to rayward:</p><blockquote><p>Charles Barkley isn't happy: cable (his employer is TNT) is losing NBA media rights to the big three, Disney (ESPN/ABC), NBC, and Amazon. Concentration of wealth in America. What could go wrong? America loves its entertainment, no entertainment more than sports. Ask me again why America isn't as innovative as in the past? Way down here the big story is sports, namely the state's flagship university. No, DeSantis didn't do it, again, media rights did: a lawsuit was filed Tuesday by a former high school star quarterback who in his lawsuit claims that in 2023 the University of Florida reneged on a $13.85 million plus guaranteed NIL (name, image, likeness) payoff if he signed with the University. What could go wrong? Media (that includes the internet) owns America, and by extension, Americans. </p>
<p>I read an article today that indicated the titans of Silicon Valley are signing on to the Trump campaign. I've commented many times that, like water seeking its own level, capital seeks the highest rate of return. And today, the highest rate of return for capital is Trump, who promises a large tax cut for capital, and specifically for the titans of Silicon Valley, Trump promises to back off antitrust enforcement against tech. This isn't a moral choice for capital: capital doesn't make moral choices, it's a law of nature. Like a teenage boy seeking what teenage boys seek whatever the cost: it's not morality, it's nature.</p>
</blockquote><p>Oddly, capitalism is actually a cultural system like any other. But it pretends that its brand of culture is a culture-free battle for the buffet, the devil take the hindmost. But not all cultures are on board. Just 50 years ago here, this run for the money would have seemed somewhat ugly. And the Trobriand Islanders played cricket, but the ideal game was a tie. It actually takes a lot of moral labor to create a society in which the market is eroticized more than other people, and in which people are commodified while society is operated for the benefit of commodities and their reproduction.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760627">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760627</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition</a></p><p>Votes: 223⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760627</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760627</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthropologist]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 18:50:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on That was then, this is now, NBA edition by Dinwar]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Edward Burke:</p><blockquote><p>In ancient times, sigh alas alack, at least gladiators fought to the death: entertainment value was held to be commensurate to the spectacle, someone could argue.</p>
<p>That our GDP is calibrated to such investments in ephemera constitutes a sign of woefully misplaced priorities, esp. in light in significant challenges we and our GDP face in the world today. (Remind me how much municipal and state "investment" commonly goes into the periodic construction of stadia and colosseum venues, which may not of itself be enormous, but then there's all that corruption that professional athletics has engendered, perhaps possibly maybe in post-secondary institutions of "higher learning" most of all.)</p>
</blockquote><p>As Anonymous said, most gladiators weren't killed. And it's notable that the circus--ie, chariot races--were more popular than the gladiators. Rome was built by its equivalent of NASCAR, not by its equivalent of MMA. </p>
<p>As for corruption, it depends on the definition. What Romans called normal business practice, we would call an insane amount of corruption. But in Rome it was expected. If you're my client OF COURSE I'm going to give you the lucrative stone contract to build my new Circus Minimus; that's what this relationship is about (you'll repay by having your family support me in the next election), and to not do so would be a direct insult. Giving the contract to a friend would paint me as an honorable man, someone worthy of authority; to not do so would cost me most of my status in the community. Nowadays it's considered scandalous if you even know the guy that owns the stone company; if you do, at minimum you have to disclose a potential conflict of interest and the bid review process is subject to an insane amount of oversight. My point being, before we talk about the novelty of corruption it would be wise to make sure we're comparing apples to apples.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760643">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760643</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition</a></p><p>Votes: 218⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760643</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760643</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dinwar]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 19:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on That was then, this is now, NBA edition by (Not That) Bill O'Reilly]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Andao:</p><blockquote><p>That doesn't make sense. People travel for work all the time and pay taxes according to where they live.</p>
</blockquote><p>Look up the term "jock tax." There are state/local tax laws designed not to implicate a business trip for some middle manager but to still extract their pound of flesh from unsympathetic out-of-town athletes.* I work in a professional services industry where we bill by the hour, and I have to code each of my time entries based on where I actually perform the work so we have a compliance audit trail. </p>
<p>*Hilariously, this can actually lead to situations where an athlete loses money by performing better. Forbes or WSJ or the like had an article a few years back about how Cam Newton's bonus for making the Super Bowl with Panthers was worth less than the tax liability that the state of California (where the game was played that year) would impose on his overall salary for spending a week there.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760725">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760725</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition</a></p><p>Votes: 155⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760725</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/that-was-then-this-is-now-nba-edition.html?commentID=160760725</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[(Not That) Bill O'Reilly]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 03:12:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on *GOAT* is now a free audiobook by Vulcidian]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>That picture of the goat with glasses is cringe incarnate. Have we hit peak AItman?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760512">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760512</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook</a></p><p>Votes: 188⬆ 2⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760512</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760512</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Vulcidian]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 13:22:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on *GOAT* is now a free audiobook by Edward Burke]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Vulcidian:</p><blockquote><p>That picture of the goat with glasses is cringe incarnate. Have we hit peak AItman?</p>
</blockquote><p>For some contemporaries it conjures (or can conjure) at least two associated associations:</p>
<p>1) it suggests the title and cover of The Rolling Stones' album Goats Head Soup; </p>
<p>and</p>
<p>2) with a suitable goatee of venerable length, it conjures images of The Devil (aka Lucifer, Satan), as in "Sympathy for . . .".</p>
<p>Great company for Tyler to keep for a change, get him away from his Beatles infatuations for a while.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760527">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760527</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook</a></p><p>Votes: 185⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760527</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760527</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Edward Burke]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 14:01:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on *GOAT* is now a free audiobook by blue jay]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to Edward Burke:</p><blockquote><p>For some contemporaries it conjures (or can conjure) at least two associated associations:</p>
<p>1) it suggests the title and cover of The Rolling Stones' album Goats Head Soup; </p>
<p>and</p>
<p>2) with a suitable goatee of venerable length, it conjures images of The Devil (aka Lucifer, Satan), as in "Sympathy for . . .".</p>
<p>Great company for Tyler to keep for a change, get him away from his Beatles infatuations for a while.</p>
</blockquote><p>"get him away from his Beatles infatuations for a while."</p>
<p>The rolling stones are just a bar band.  But I dig all the different tunings Keith uses.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760557">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760557</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook</a></p><p>Votes: 184⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760557</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760557</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[blue jay]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 14:56:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on *GOAT* is now a free audiobook by Daniel Plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>My guess is that the voice is Wallace Michael Shawn aka The Toy Story Dinosaur.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760509">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760509</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook</a></p><p>Votes: 184⬆ 0⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760509</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/05/goat-is-now-a-free-audiobook.html?commentID=160760509</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Plant]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 13:13:06 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>