<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 22:09:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Acemoglu, Johnson and Robinson Win Nobel Prize for Institutions and Prosperity by Vulcidian]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>"In an empirical breakdown, Acemoglu and Restrepo suggest that what has happened in the 1990s and especially since 2000 is mediocre-robots. As a result, there has been a decline in labor on net. Thus, Acemoglu is more negative than many economists on automation, at least as it has occurred recently."</p>
<p>Bingo. My favorite example is comparing Microsoft Excel 2003 to all of the subsequent versions. I'm probably to lazy to write it, but I would love a book or documentary that explains how we got from clean, efficient, and open source code to lobbying for nuclear reactors to for gated and bloated code that simulates the gold standard, serves you ads, and replaces journalists in under 20 years.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity.html?commentID=160822808">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity.html?commentID=160822808</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity</a></p><p>Votes: 54⬆ 8⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity.html?commentID=160822808</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity.html?commentID=160822808</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Vulcidian]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 12:26:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Acemoglu, Johnson and Robinson Win Nobel Prize for Institutions and Prosperity by Ricardo]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Reply to H:</p><blockquote><p>I suspect the impact of institutions is overrated. It’s a feel-good story that suggests everyone can get rich by making some easy changes completely within their control. But if it were that easy, why haven’t most countries done it?</p>
<p>This explanation of dictators who would rather rule over poverty than let their countries get richer seems not very plausible. For one thing, there are certainly some dictators who have remained in power despite wealth (like Saudi Arabia, China, etc.)—indeed, in those countries, growing wealth is part of the bargain that creates popular support for the dictatorship. Even in countries where the dictators lost power like South Korea or Spain, their descendants are usually still living pretty well. For another thing, it seems like ruling over a rich country where you could be a powerful billionaire would be a lot more fun than ruling over some impoverished country where you’re at the mercy of the IMF or USA and would probably be afraid to travel abroad on fear of arrest or a coup at home. There may be dictators who hold their country back at the margin, sure, but that’s because they know institutional reform won’t get them much.</p>
<p>The two examples are also highly confounded. North and South Korea were on opposite sides of the Cold War, and as a recent paper showed, the greater prosperity of democracies in modern times is due to the US treating them better: https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4912929. Areas where European colonizers were more likely to survive also had better natural conditions and demographic replacement as well.</p>
</blockquote><p>I am skeptical of some of their work (and there are critiques that focus purely on statistical methods and methodology) but the point of the institutional argument is that institutions are <b>not</b> easy to change. Countries inherit the legal system, tax system, and civil service set up by prior generations. If these were installed by elites whose primary objective was exploitation and resource extraction, change is very difficult.</p>
<p>Also, the choice is not between being impoverished or being rich. There are lots of corrupt, poorly governed middle income countries out there that grow enough for long enough periods of time to give people hope (and maybe make them complacent) but not enough to break into the rich country club. China, despite all of the hype, is still a middle income country. And you have to do something pretty bad and piss off all of the powerful countries in the world before you fear arrest abroad. Robert Mugabe's wife goes to Hong Kong for shopping trips. You might be surprised at the number of politicians among U.S. allies who own luxury  properties in the U.S. and no one says anything about it. If there is no accountability at home, accountability abroad is rarer still.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity.html?commentID=160822805">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity.html?commentID=160822805</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity</a></p><p>Votes: 46⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity.html?commentID=160822805</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/10/acemoglu-johnson-and-robinson-win-nobel-for-institutions-and-prosperity.html?commentID=160822805</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ricardo]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 12:16:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>