<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 22:06:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on What is the gravest outright mistake out there? by dan1111]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Wow, this is what you pick as an example of an outright mistake, not a disagreement? </p>
<p>The idea that the US high drug prices are net beneficial is very, very debatable. This is a broken system that lacks market-based price mechanisms, and people who normally favor free markets bend over backwards to argue that this is good because it subsidizes good stuff. In what other context would they make that same argument?</p>
<p>Plus the primary proposal on the table, allowing Medicare to negotiate drug prices, is arguably a move in a market-based direction. (It's a global market, so no the US government is not "the only customer" in that context).</p>
<p>Personally I think that, while artificially high prices no doubt subsidize some good stuff, the argument that the harm outweighs the good is much stronger.</p>
<p>This system does not do a good job incentivizing research into the most important treatments that deliver the most value. There is little incentive to develop more efficient, cheaper treatments, either. </p>
<p>Plus there is the obvious opportunity cost issue: money spent on drugs with bonkers prices could be spent on other things that save or improve lives.</p>
<p>I think this issue is a major blind spot for US conservatives. But even if you disagree, surely we shouldn't put this one beyond reasonable debate?</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/what-is-the-gravest-outright-mistake-out-there.html?commentID=160773463">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/what-is-the-gravest-outright-mistake-out-there.html?commentID=160773463</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/what-is-the-gravest-outright-mistake-out-there.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-is-the-gravest-outright-mistake-out-there">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/what-is-the-gravest-outright-mistake-out-there.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=what-is-the-gravest-outright-mistake-out-there</a></p><p>Votes: 177⬆ 20⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/what-is-the-gravest-outright-mistake-out-there.html?commentID=160773463</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/06/what-is-the-gravest-outright-mistake-out-there.html?commentID=160773463</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[dan1111]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 11:10:01 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>