<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:05:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on The polity that is Hawaii by Mcro]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm sorry Tyler but you misunderstand Hawaii politics and I don't think your informant is doing you any favors. </p>
<p>1. Hawaii is small-c conservative only in the sense that there is broad suspicion of economic development. A popular anti-developmentalist ethos pervades the culture and cashes out as disgust at the way that outside investors, mostly 'haoles from the mainland', are perceived to have ravaged the state and made life impossible for most of its inhabitants. This is also a well-spring for indigenous radicalism, which is an important feature of the cultural landscape (See the Thirty Meter Telescope). </p>
<p>2. The reduction in income tax is not popular on any kind of "pro-business" grounds. It is popular because there is a brutal cost of living crisis that is pushing people out of their communities. It's an emergency measure to staunch the bleeding caused by stratospheric increases in housing costs. People are desperate for relief. </p>
<p>3. Hawaii's inability to pass cannabis legislation has nothing to do with cultural conservatism. Because Hawaii is a single party state, the ruling party is a corrupt patronage network. Attempts to legalize cannabis have included licensing requirements to severely restricted growers' licenses to a small pool of inevitably politically connected individuals. The problem is that Hawaii already has huge numbers of small cannabis farmers. Cannabis legislative efforts have been viewed as another attempt by 'The Businessmen and Politicians' to steal opportunity from small local growers. There is an entire cultural politics here around the local farmer 'perpetuating the life of the land in righteousness' versus the big mainland businesses that will come in and buy everything up.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/07/the-polity-that-is-hawaii.html?commentID=160780192">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/07/the-polity-that-is-hawaii.html?commentID=160780192</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/07/the-polity-that-is-hawaii.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-polity-that-is-hawaii">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/07/the-polity-that-is-hawaii.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-polity-that-is-hawaii</a></p><p>Votes: 85⬆ 3⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/07/the-polity-that-is-hawaii.html?commentID=160780192</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/07/the-polity-that-is-hawaii.html?commentID=160780192</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mcro]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 11:19:23 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>