<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></title><description><![CDATA[MR Quick Takes]]></description><link>https://github.com/mondain-dev/mr-quick-takes</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 22:07:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mondain-dev.github.io/mr-quick-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Crime vs. disorder by y81]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>1/11/17--"My views [of Black Lives Matter] are pretty simple, namely that I am a fan of the movement.  Police in this country kill, beat, arrest, fine, and confiscate the property of black people at unfair and disproportionate rates. "</p>
<p>So we have the urban environments Tyler wanted.  If you don't like it, don't live in DC, live in a gated community in NoVa, like Tyler does.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/crime-vs-disorder.html?commentID=160816872">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/crime-vs-disorder.html?commentID=160816872</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/crime-vs-disorder.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=crime-vs-disorder">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/crime-vs-disorder.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=crime-vs-disorder</a></p><p>Votes: 50⬆ 7⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/crime-vs-disorder.html?commentID=160816872</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/crime-vs-disorder.html?commentID=160816872</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[y81]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 18:14:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on Crime vs. disorder by Phil S.]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>A little over a month ago, my son's parked car was hit and run at high speed (body shop estimate ~50 mph) on a Saturday night.  His car totalled.  Debris from his car AND the car that hit him strewn over the street, including parts that could identify make and model (and maybe year and paint color) of car that hit him.  </p>
<p>Police didn't even come in person to take report or look at any evidence - just a phone report.</p>
<p>Did that go in the city's crime reports?  I'm skeptical...</p>
<p>Did it change my son's perception of living in the city?  Darn tootin'</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/crime-vs-disorder.html?commentID=160816847">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/crime-vs-disorder.html?commentID=160816847</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/crime-vs-disorder.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=crime-vs-disorder">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/crime-vs-disorder.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=crime-vs-disorder</a></p><p>Votes: 69⬆ 4⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/crime-vs-disorder.html?commentID=160816847</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/crime-vs-disorder.html?commentID=160816847</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Phil S.]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 17:45:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comment on “Despair” and Death in the United States by Crusader]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I frequently believe and argue, like many fans of technology and capitalism, that to some degree we should just be happy we have dishwashers, DoorDash, and GDP, and just focus on getting more. It’s undeniable the US is leading in material QOL and it’s undeniable that we remain the most desired country to immigrate to. That’s certainly worth something.</p>
<p>When we think about the future, perhaps the only true bipartisan thing in America is that everyone wants max QOL and as little work as possible. Many of the extreme progressives dream of a society where they can just do pottery, and many of the extreme conservatives, just using Thiel as an example, envision an automated future where presumably everyone in America perhaps gets UBI and is displaced by AI.</p>
<p>Regardless of if you agree with me on the above, we can probably agree that no person in America is loudly arguing for less QOL and more work. Can you imagine that POTUS platform?</p>
<p>But if we look at the population that most closely matches the “utopia” that many dream of (generally white stay at home moms, without careers, and of older children), we see the highest rates of anxiety and depression (nearly 30% AFAIK).</p>
<p>Presumably some of it is because they have better access to doctors and diagnoses, but it can’t all be that and there’s obviously a huge issue here somewhere.</p>
<p>I find it hard to imagine that the key to their happiness is higher GDP, perhaps self-driving Waymos or AR glasses. Or maybe if we can get grocery delivery down to 7 minutes by using e-bikes, they’ll finally see nirvana.</p>
<p>So what does that tell us who push for and celebrate progress? Are we marching ourselves towards an ending that we think we want but don’t actually want? Like some of the FIRE people on Reddit that retire at 30 and within 5 years are confused and miserable?</p>
<p>Anecdotally I’ve been happiest when I’m working hard on something and am excited about the future changing due to my current actions. And the least happy when I feel like life is stagnant and there’s not much I can do.</p>
<p>It’s so obvious in a lot of cases that things like the lottery or early riches and retirement generally lead to disaster and unhappiness. What will 300M people do if Andrew Yang or Sam Altmans visions comes true? What would 1B people do? I find it hard to imagine we’d all joyously turn to hobbies for the rest of our lives.</p>
<p>Perhaps the boring reality is that life is pretty long and as much as we complain about work, the alternative isn’t all sunshine and roses either. Arguably we should optimize for more or equal work, but of more meaningful and fulfilling varieties. My guess is that companies did this weird cultural thing in the 2010s of promoting chill culture of ping pong and happy hours, when ironically many people would probably prefer a more intense culture as long as it was real work and meaningful. </p>
<p>—-</p>
<p>I just scribbled this out on mobile and just wanted to note that I don’t know the answer to this. I feel conflicted between the above concerns and my general faith in “progress”. Perhaps someone can figure out how to reconcile this.</p>
<hr/><p>Comment URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/despair-and-death-in-the-united-states.html?commentID=160816615">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/despair-and-death-in-the-united-states.html?commentID=160816615</a></p><p>Post URL: <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/despair-and-death-in-the-united-states.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=despair-and-death-in-the-united-states">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/despair-and-death-in-the-united-states.html?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=despair-and-death-in-the-united-states</a></p><p>Votes: 54⬆ 4⬇</p>]]></description><link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/despair-and-death-in-the-united-states.html?commentID=160816615</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/09/despair-and-death-in-the-united-states.html?commentID=160816615</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Crusader]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 05:40:29 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>